<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>Unknown</builtInGames>
        <colors>Unknown</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80</cpu>
        <description>
What a weird system ! After their Combat Lunaire, Stellar Electronique announced a brand new and revolutionary system : Micromat, also named &amp;quot;micro-ordinateur de jeux, fonctions universelles&amp;quot;, i.e. &amp;quot;gaming micro-computer, universal fonctions&amp;quot;. What a program ! It seems to be an original mix between a check board gaming system, a micro-computer and a video-game system !!

The system uses almost the same plastic case as the Combat Lunaire system, though it is black here. There is a check board built-in the case used to play checkerboard games like tic-tac-toe, checkers, chess, etc. All moves of a game session can be saved on tape, and reloaded to finish it !

But games can also be loaded from cartridge, tape and even vinyl records ! The system can be connected to a TV to play video games, though there is a built-in display (8 digits, 14 segments)... There are sound features but specs are unknown.

Interaction is made through a knob and fire switch (button?) built-in the part of the system. There is also a 18 keys keypad next to the checkboard. Games listed in the press release were : tic-tac-toe, checker, chess, bridge, lunar landing, star war, chess, go... The system is described as &amp;quot;the first universal mini-computer of great power mainly aimed at games&amp;quot;.

It is not clear if this system was ever released, but it was for sure a very original and interesting object !
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Unknown</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/stellar-electronique_micromat_s.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>controls built-in the system : 1 dial, 1 switch, 18 keys keyboard</keyboard>
        <language>Unknown</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Stellar Electronique</manufacturer>
        <media>vinyl records (!), magnetic tapes, cartridges</media>
        <name>Micromat</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>France</origin>
        <peripherals>memory expansion</peripherals>
        <ports>video output, tape / vinyl record interface</ports>
        <power>Unknown</power>
        <price>4000 FF (France, June 1979)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>Unknown</ram>
        <rom></rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;MICROMAT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/stellar-electronique_micromat.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>(38 x 22 x 7 cm)</size>
        <sound>Yes (specs unknown)</sound>
        <speed>2 MHz</speed>
        <text></text>
        <type></type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>june 1979</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
