<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>10 Games (Moving target, S.L. Target, Tennis, Soccer, Squash, Practice, Drag race, Stunt Cycle, Motor Cross, Enduro)</builtInGames>
        <colors>Colour</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>General Instruments AY-3-8512 (4 color pong games + 2 shoting games) + AY-3-8760 (4 motor cycle games)</cpu>
        <description>
Though this it looks like a common European pong system, the Poppy 9017 is quite particular for it offers 4 pongs games, 2 shooting games AND 4 motor cycle games in the same case... wow

The 4 classic pongs games (Tennis, Soccer, Squash, Practice) and 2 shooting games (Moving target, S.L. Target) are almost certainly offered by the General Instrument AY-3-8512 chipset. The shooting games are only playable with the optional light gun. The 4 motor cycle games (Drag race, Stunt Cycle, Motor Cross, Enduro) are powered by the General Instruments AY-3-8760 chipset. This two GI chipsets are used in this system, which is quite unsual

While the 6 pong games are selected with a knob, the 4 motor cycle games are selected through 4 buttons. Seven swicthes offer the folowing functions: Serve (auto/manu), Ball angle (20&amp;deg;, 60&amp;deg;), Ball speed (high/low), Bat size (small/large), Cycle (hard/easy), Power (on/off) and Game type (Paddle/Rifle or Cycle). The two detachable paddles have no fire button...

The Tele-Partner Model G is the same system.

________

Thanks to Emil Panasiuk for the picture.
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Unknown</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/poppy_9017.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>2 detachable paddles with no fire buttons</keyboard>
        <language>10 Games (Moving target, S.L. Target, Tennis, Soccer, Squash, Practice, Drag race, Stunt Cycle, Motor Cross, Enduro)</language>
        <links>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=1192</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Poppy</manufacturer>
        <media></media>
        <name>9017 - Colour TV Game</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Europe</origin>
        <peripherals>Light-gun</peripherals>
        <ports>RF TV video output, Light gun connector, Power In</ports>
        <power>External PSU 9v DC or 6 x 1,5v batteries</power>
        <price>Unknown</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram></ram>
        <rom></rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size></size>
        <sound>Built-in speaker</sound>
        <speed></speed>
        <text></text>
        <type></type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>? 1982</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
