<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amstrad CPC, BBC Micro, Camputers Lynx, Commodore 64, Enterprise, Memotech MTX, MSX, Nascom, Oric, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>The sequel to &lt;a href="/game/colossal-adventure"&gt;Colossal Adventure&lt;/a&gt; is an interactive fiction game with a VERB NOUN interface. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The fantasy setting takes a clear influence from &lt;a href="/search/quick?gamegroup=Lord+of+the+Rings"&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/a&gt;. After centuries of harmony, Middle Earth has hit problems due to a cataclysmic sequence of events - a crop failure leading to animals turning violent, and then an attack from a mysterious enemy to the north. The evil Demon Lord Alagiarept is discovered to be responsible, and as such the Wizards are given a week to beat him, before Middle Earth must surrender.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You play a rookie magician with Meditation, Mysticism and
Moneymaking skills. While the main war goes on, you attempt a much bolder mission - locate the four Stones-of-the-Elements and the Medallion of Life to enter Alagiarept's Dark Tower and kill him.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Your quest will take you through Beaches, Moors and Rocky Outcrops, as well as more specific locations such as the Pillar in the Desert, the Cave of the Sun-Dial and the Mills of God. Wolves, skeletal hands, sharks and octopuses must be dealt with.</description>
        <developedBy>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Adventure Quest</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United Kingdom</country>
                <developer>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</developer>
                <publisher>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1983</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1983</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/531980-adventure-quest-atari-8-bit-screenshot-welcome-and-starting.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/531981-adventure-quest-atari-8-bit-screenshot-yuck.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/531982-adventure-quest-atari-8-bit-screenshot-sigh-women-never-stay.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/531983-adventure-quest-atari-8-bit-screenshot-reading-the-scroll.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/531984-adventure-quest-atari-8-bit-screenshot-i-m-a-quitter.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/adventure-quest</url>
    </game>
</games>
