<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Apple II, Commodore 64, PC Booter | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Bannercatch&lt;/i&gt; is an educational action game for two players. The game is a variation of capture the flag; two human players compete against Max and his team of robots. To win the game, the players need to work as a team to travel to Max's zone of the playfield, capture the flag, and bring it back safely back before Max is able to capture the players flag. Each time the players successfully capture one of Max's flags, part of his face will be revealed; the goal is to try to see all of Max's face. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To help with this quest, the game includes maps which provide an overview of the entire playing field (each player will only be able to see a small portion on the screen at a time). Also, hints about his flags whereabouts can be gained by tricking Max into telling about it. This is done by positioning a player over one of the robot sensors and attempting to communicate with Max disguised as one of his robots. Since Max talks to his robots in binary, the player will need to translate a series of binary numbers to convince Max to reveal clues about his flags location. At any time during the game the player can freeze the action; this allows for checking the maps or taking a rest.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game features five different levels of difficulty along with a demonstration mode. Points are earned for successfully capturing the flag, tagging a robot which is carrying your flag, and winning the game. </description>
        <developedBy>Tom Snyder Productions, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Action, Educational</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Bannercatch</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Scholastic, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Tom Snyder Productions, Inc.</developer>
                <publisher>Scholastic, Inc.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1984</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1984</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/bannercatch</url>
    </game>
</games>
