<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Commodore 64, Dragon 32/64, TRS-80 CoCo | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/322642-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/322643-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-back-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/322644-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-media.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Danger Ranger&lt;/i&gt; is an early, fixed-screen platform game. It is set on two screens.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On the first screen, consisting of five platform floors, you must jump between the platforms with your Ranger, picking up all the keys. To make things more complicated, some floors are inhabited by dangerous birds or bats, which you can shoot with your gun. Furthermore, the left and right boundaries of the screen are patrolled by floating objects which shoot beams whenever you are on the same level as they. They can also be shot down, but regenerate soon afterwards. Since your Ranger cannot jump high enough to reach platforms above his head, your only way to collect missed keys is to take the lift at the bottom of the screen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On the second screen, your Ranger walks along platforms to pick up treasure chests. Deadly masks are placed around the screen, and must be shot down in order to progress. Meanwhile, a deadly rain falls both from above and below, hindering your steps. Once both screens are completed, you go on to the next level where the enemies are more numerous.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game can be played in the usual green, buff and black/white colour schemes on the Dragon, whereas the Tandy version plays in NTSC artifact colours; orange and blue.</description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Danger Ranger</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>MicroDeal Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United Kingdom</country>
                <publisher>MicroDeal Ltd.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1984</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1984</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/508002-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/508003-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-screenshot-select-level.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/508004-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-screenshot-starting-level-1-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/508005-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-screenshot-i-shot-one-of-the-floating.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/508006-danger-ranger-atari-8-bit-screenshot-i-lost-all-my-lives-but.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/danger-ranger</url>
    </game>
</games>
