<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor></alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Dodge Racer&lt;/i&gt; is a &lt;a href="/game/power-racer"&gt;Head On&lt;/a&gt; variant. The player races his car around a circuit consisting of six lanes and has to avoid crashing into another car that races in the opposite direction. To avoid the opposite car the player has to switch lanes, something that can only be done in the middle of each straight. The player double the speed by pressing a button. When at normal speed the player can only move one lane at a time, while at double speed he can move two. On all lanes there are dots that have to be collected to be able to move on to the next level. The game ends after five crashes. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are a number of variants of the game, with different options turned on or off. This include choosing if dots should be restored after a crash, whether there should be one or two computer controlled cars and whether the crash cars can accelerate or not. The game can be played by up to four players who take turns playing. There is also a competitive mode where one player takes control of the crash car and has to hit the other player. </description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Racing / Driving</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Dodge Racer</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Synapse Software Corporation</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <publisher>Synapse Software Corporation</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1981</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1981</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609267-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609268-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-options.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609269-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-starting-out.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609270-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-crashing.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609272-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-level-completed.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609271-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-game-over.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609273-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-up-against-two-crash-cars.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/609274-dodge-racer-atari-8-bit-screenshot-multiplayer.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/dodge-racer</url>
    </game>
</games>
