<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Apple II, Commodore PET/CBM, TRS-80 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Dunjonquest: Hellfire Warrior&lt;/i&gt; is a true sequel to &lt;a href="/game/dunjonquest-temple-of-apshai"&gt;Temple of Apshai&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The player resumes his role as Brian Hammerhand and starts in the town he saved from the evil ant god in the previous mentioned game. The town has flourished and expanded, but the protagonist is haunted by a recurring dream. In the dream Death himself stops him from saving the warrior queen Brynhild from the depths of the world. Brian decides to venture into the dungeons once more to find this legendary woman and return her to sunlight.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Gameplay is similar to earlier games using the top-down view to offer the player a dungeon crawl experience. The game allows importing of characters from earlier games and is meant for characters with 21,000 experience points and above. The expanded town allows for purchasing better equipment than before including special draughts that give temporary attribute boosts. It's now also possible to enchant ordinary weapons and armour with magical properties. The player now also has various optional objectives that may be fulfilled.</description>
        <developedBy>Automated Simulations, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Role-Playing (RPG)</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Dunjonquest: Hellfire Warrior</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Automated Simulations, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Automated Simulations, Inc.</developer>
                <publisher>Automated Simulations, Inc.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1982</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1982</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/dunjonquest-hellfire-warrior</url>
    </game>
</games>
