<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Arcade, Atari 2600, Atari 5200, ColecoVision, Commodore 64, VIC-20 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Gorf&lt;/i&gt; is a game that consists of five levels:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first level called &lt;i&gt;Astro Battles&lt;/i&gt; has the player's ship behind a defensive shield, defending against an alien attack. The level is a top-down view, with the player's ship and shield on one side and the aliens on the other side; this level bears the most resemblance to &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=Space+Invaders"&gt;Space Invaders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;The second level called &lt;i&gt;Laser Attack&lt;/i&gt; is made up of a formation of ships, with some that swoop down and a laser that fires at the player's ship. Bonus ships also tend to appear in this level.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;The third level is called &lt;i&gt;Galaxians&lt;/i&gt;, and as the name suggests it is very similar to the game &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=Galaxian"&gt;Galaxian&lt;/a&gt; with ships constantly dive bombing the player's spaceship. This mission only appears in the Arcade version.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;The fourth level called &lt;i&gt;Space Warp&lt;/i&gt;, has the player entering hyperspace.. The viewpoint switches from a top-down view to a behind-the-ship view. One by one, alien vessels will come out and fly in a circular formation shooting at the player's ship with the players goal being to destroy each one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;The fifth and final level is called &lt;i&gt;Flag Ship&lt;/i&gt;. In this level, the player does not fight a wave of enemies, but a single one which happens to be a large Flag Ship with a  weak spot which is its core. Hitting the weak spot will instantly destroy it, but the player must first shoot through a similar shield that the player had in the first level.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Finishing the game increases the player's rank and starts the game over at level 1 with a faster game speed for more challenge.</description>
        <developedBy>Dave Nutting Associates, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Gorf</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Roklan Corporation</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Dave Nutting Associates, Inc.</developer>
                <ported>Roklan Corporation</ported>
                <publisher>Roklan Corporation</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1982</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1982</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/149557-gorf-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/149558-gorf-atari-8-bit-screenshot-game-start.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/149559-gorf-atari-8-bit-screenshot-making-some-inroads.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/149560-gorf-atari-8-bit-screenshot-the-second-section.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/149561-gorf-atari-8-bit-screenshot-there-s-that-lazer.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/149562-gorf-atari-8-bit-screenshot-game-over.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/gorf</url>
    </game>
</games>
