<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Acorn 32-bit, Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Amstrad PCW, Apple II, Atari ST, Commodore 64, DOS, Macintosh, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Aquatania has recently become the land of misfortunes, due to a group of plotting witches. The task of finding five charms and a magic bracelet to put things right falls on you.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And you need a change of luck, because events in this game often emphasise the slings and arrows of outrageous fortune. You get hit by a car, fall a great height, sprayed with cheese sandwich and more! Being the guinea pig in this strange world will drive you insane - if this jinxed land doesn't do it first. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jinxter&lt;/i&gt; is an interactive fiction with graphics title that takes a realistic world of people and situations, and then plays with the boundaries to create a strange and puzzling world. Characters are all getting on with their own tasks, and getting them to help you is usually a case of making sure something's in it for them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Dialogue aims to add a comic touch to proceedings. Puzzles can often be solved in multiple ways, but the most obvious way is not always the correct one. Due to the presence of a Guardian, you can't actually die.</description>
        <developedBy>Magnetic Scrolls</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Jinxter</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Rainbird Software</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United Kingdom</country>
                <developer>Magnetic Scrolls</developer>
                <ean13>5 012439 103196</ean13>
                <publisher>Rainbird Software</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1988</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1988</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/453660-jinxter-atari-8-bit-screenshot-opening-story.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/453661-jinxter-atari-8-bit-screenshot-this-is-version-1-2-and-a-jolly.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/453662-jinxter-atari-8-bit-screenshot-you-re-on-the-buss.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/jinxter</url>
    </game>
</games>
