<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Amstrad PCW, Atari ST, BBC Micro, Commodore 64, DOS, Macintosh, MSX, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Travel back to the Age of Chivalry when knights were bold, galloping across the countryside and rescuing damsels in distress. This game recreates the time of wizards and the Knights of the Round Table. &lt;i&gt;Lancelot&lt;/i&gt; is a three-part interactive fiction adventure, spanning the complete saga from the foundation of the Order to its finest hour - the quest for the Holy Grail. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Guide Lancelot through his many exploits at Camelot, battle with wayward knights, and win the love of Guinever and Elaine. The challenge which has fascinated treasure hunters through the centuries is now yours - and you'll need all your strength, wit and valor to achieve your goal. To get the highest possible score, you should only kill combat foes when it is absolutely essential to survival.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game's command set includes the ability to issue instructions to other knights, and to automatically GO TO a place you have previously visited.</description>
        <developedBy>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Lancelot</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Mandarin Software</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <comments>Disk release</comments>
                <country> United Kingdom</country>
                <developer>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</developer>
                <publisher>Mandarin Software</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1988</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1988</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/543674-lancelot-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen-and-introduction.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/543675-lancelot-atari-8-bit-screenshot-the-game-starts-here.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/543676-lancelot-atari-8-bit-screenshot-a-battle-with-the-black-knight.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/lancelot</url>
    </game>
</games>
