<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Apple II, Commodore PET/CBM, TRS-80 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/249846-lords-of-karma-apple-ii-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/249847-lords-of-karma-apple-ii-back-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/249848-lords-of-karma-apple-ii-media.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/282712-lords-of-karma-atari-8-bit-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/282718-lords-of-karma-atari-8-bit-back-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/282719-lords-of-karma-atari-8-bit-media.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>The first clue as to the unconventional nature of this text adventure is the scant description within the game manual. Unlike most games of its era, &lt;i&gt;Lords of Karma&lt;/i&gt; doesn't rely on a written narrative peppered with enticing illustrations to prepare and color the player's experience. Even Lords of Karma's plot is to be discovered in-game, just like the vistas and scents of its magical world. There is treasure, of course, and deadly foes, but what to do with the spoils of adventure? You only know that you quest for &amp;quot;karma points&amp;quot; to take to heaven, and that you begin in the central square of the mythical city of Golconda.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The standard abbreviations and two-word commands move you through this text-only, turn-based adventure, but don't stand there gawking. While looking twice can reveal something missed the first time, it will also put you in the maw of a hungry crocodile. Happily, rebirth is just around the corner. Dying doesn't end your game -- the karmic wheel keeps turning. It simply strips you of your worldly goods and puts you on a mountaintop. The map is fixed, and the karma points are yours to keep, so progress belongs to the persistent (and those who find the in-game hint book).</description>
        <developedBy>Microcomputer Games, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Lords of Karma</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>The Avalon Hill Game Company</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Microcomputer Games, Inc.</developer>
                <publisher>The Avalon Hill Game Company</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1981</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1981</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/lords-of-karma</url>
    </game>
</games>
