<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Commodore 64 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Build your own monster and send it to fight against other monsters. You can choose between 12 different monster types (Tyro, Hominid, Arachnid, Worm, Wasp and more). Then you may select among 11 different enhancements for each monster type (tentacles, sting, fiery breath...) and finally equip your creature with a weapon (rifle, laser gun, flamethrower...).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Every enhancement and every weapon costs money. To earn some money your monster has to win fights on different battlefields (desert, jungle, swamp and more). These fights are similar to Archon but vary on their winning conditions. &amp;quot;Destruction&amp;quot; (kill the enemy monster), &amp;quot;Flag Collection&amp;quot; (capture the flag) and &amp;quot;The Horde&amp;quot; (kill more computer controlled Hordlings than your monster rival).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The 3 difficulty levels of the game represent 3 game variations.
The beginner level lets you pick a precreated monster and sends you right out into the battlefield. The intermediate level gives you some money to create and enhance/equip your monster. Then you can send your creature off to fight and possibly win additional money. The tournament level is more of a career mode. You are allowed to own more than one monster and get access to the corrals, which lets you save your different monsters and every contest result.</description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Action, Strategy/Tactics</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Mail Order Monsters</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Electronic Arts, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <publisher>Electronic Arts, Inc.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/150395-mail-order-monsters-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/mail-order-monsters</url>
    </game>
</games>
