<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Amstrad PCW, Apple II, Atari ST, Commodore 64, DOS, Macintosh | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/178304-moonmist-atari-8-bit-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/178305-moonmist-atari-8-bit-back-cover.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>Tamara Lynd has recently become engaged to Jack Tresyllian, a wealthy owner of the Tresyllian Castle in Cornwall, England. Shortly afterwards, she began seeing a ghost-like figure, a mysterious White Lady, who has allegedly been haunting the castle for centuries. A series of events and dark suspicions involving hidden treasure convince Tamara that her life is in danger. She contacts a friend of hers, a young American detective, asking him to travel to the castle and investigate the mystery.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Moonmist&lt;/i&gt; is a text adventure game. In the beginning the player chooses between four different scenarios, represented by the colors red, blue, yellow and green. Each scenario has different tasks, a different criminal, and different treasure. The game has a built-in clock, and must be completed before 6:00 am in-game time, otherwise it ends prematurely. Depending on the player's choice of the protagonist's gender, characters may react differently to his or her actions.</description>
        <developedBy>Infocom, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Moonmist</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Infocom, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Infocom, Inc.</developer>
                <publisher>Infocom, Inc.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/168307-moonmist-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen-introduction.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/168309-moonmist-atari-8-bit-screenshot-the-game-asks-me-a-few-questions.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/moonmist</url>
    </game>
</games>
