<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Commodore 64 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Napoleon at Waterloo&lt;/i&gt; is a real-time strategy game which covers the battle of Waterloo (1815).The player controls Napoleon Bonaparte's army and has to defeat the enemy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At first glance, the game has the distinctive look of a wargame: a top-down map with abstract symbols representing the terrain and units. However, everything is in real-time and therefore the complexity has been toned down. The only thing the player does is giving move orders by choosing a unit and moving the cursor to the place it should move to. Those orders are not carried out instantly; each movement takes a certain amount of time depending on terrain and unit type. Battles are initiated automatically when a unit moves close to a hostile. Then they basically exchange blows until one unit lost all of its soldiers. The game also factors in fatigue and morale.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The time is measured with an in-game clock and a match ends after eleven hours (30 minutes in real-time). If the player has won a match depends on the reached score which is based on the casualties.</description>
        <developedBy>Krentek Software</developedBy>
        <genre>Strategy/Tactics</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Napoleon at Waterloo</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Krentek Software</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States,</country>
                <developer>Krentek Software</developer>
                <publisher>Krentek Software</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1984</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1984</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/napoleon-at-waterloo</url>
    </game>
</games>
