<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amstrad CPC, Commodore 16, Plus/4, Commodore 64, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/263638-ninja-master-atari-8-bit-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/263639-ninja-master-atari-8-bit-back-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/263637-ninja-master-atari-8-bit-media.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Ninja Master&lt;/i&gt; combines four small sub games into one. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You are a trainee ninja. You want to impress your peers and become a true ninja. The time for the annual games has come around and you must compete and succeed at these games to achieve your goal. The games consist of four tests:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Test 1: The arrow test&lt;br&gt;
Arrows fly at you from off-screen, both right and left, high, middle and low. You must stop them hitting you by punching or kicking the arrow, so not only do you have to hit the right key, you have to do it at just the right time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Test 2: Breaking a block of wood&lt;br&gt;
Two keys are designated 'Right power' and 'Left power'. You must hit these alternately to build up as much power as you can within a time limit. With enough power the wood breaks and the crowd cheers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Test 3: The Shuriken star test&lt;br&gt;
Similar to the arrow test, stars fly at you from off-screen and must be blocked by hitting the right key at the right time. However the starts travel faster and, 'coz you're using your ninja sword and not your fist &amp;amp; feet, you have greater range so there's less time to react.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Test 4: The blow dart test&lt;br&gt;
Here you must use a blow-gun to hit targets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In all tests there is a qualifying score and you have three attempts to beat that score.
Succeed and you progress on to the next test.
Fail and it's back to the beginning.</description>
        <developedBy>Tron Software</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Ninja Master</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Firebird Software Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> France,</country>
                <developer>Tron Software</developer>
                <ean13>5 012439 000877</ean13>
                <publisher>Firebird Software Ltd.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/ninja-master</url>
    </game>
</games>
