<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor></alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/215048-plattermania-atari-8-bit-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/215049-plattermania-atari-8-bit-back-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/215050-plattermania-atari-8-bit-media.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Plattermania&lt;/i&gt; is set in a circus and can accommodate one to four players. The player controls a clown up on stage who has 12 poles. As the clown, each player starts the game with 10 platters. Before the start of each player's turn, the number of platters which must be spun simultaneously is displayed. To reach the goal, the player must have the correct number of plates spinning at once for at least 8 seconds. Platters will fall if they start to wobble and the player does not move the clown to it and spin it up soon enough. They will also fall if they are spun too hard. If the player breaks three platters without achieving the 8-second goal, the turn ends. Otherwise, the turn lasts until a platter falls and breaks after the 8-second goal has been achieved. Bonus multipliers for score can be earned by keeping platters spinning beyond the 8-second goal. Once all players have had a turn, the scores of all players will be shown on screen. Each time a player meets the goal, the player is moved up one level. If a player fails two turns in a row, they will be dropped down a level. When a player runs out of platters, the game is over.</description>
        <developedBy>Epyx, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>PlatterMania</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Epyx, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Epyx, Inc.</developer>
                <publisher>Epyx, Inc.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1982</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1982</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/544907-plattermania-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/544908-plattermania-atari-8-bit-screenshot-goal-for-level-1.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/544909-plattermania-atari-8-bit-screenshot-gameplay-so-far-i-have.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/544910-plattermania-atari-8-bit-screenshot-oops-a-platter-is-starting.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/544911-plattermania-atari-8-bit-screenshot-game-over-well-i-didn.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/plattermania</url>
    </game>
</games>
