<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Commodore 64, MSX, PC-88, PC-98 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Puzzle Panic consists of a series of small pattern-based puzzles, through which you guide Benny (a light-bulb) to the correct answers. Each level can be played individually, or in sequence as part of a larger puzzle, where each level is signified by a unique symbol, that users must discover to complete the final puzzle.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Some puzzles are timed challenges, such as &amp;quot;Color Climb&amp;quot;, where Benny must climb a series of coloured steps, with clues to the correct colour provided at the top of the screen. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Others are pattern based, such as &amp;quot;Triangles First&amp;quot;, where Benny must touch all triangles on the screen, followed by squares, then pentagons, etc. In these levels, Benny must also avoid being captured by a Devil-shaped enemy who is chasing him.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Every level requires the player to recognise some form of shape, colour, number and/or spatial pattern.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Completing each level reveals a series of gates containing different symbols, and passage through these gates will help Benny discover the relationship between the symbols and the levels. In the final level, the &amp;quot;metasequence&amp;quot;, Benny must correctly identify the symbol representing each level, and select them in the order that they were played.</description>
        <developedBy>Fun and Games</developedBy>
        <genre>Strategy/Tactics</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>PuzzlePanic</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Epyx, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Fun and Games</developer>
                <publisher>Epyx, Inc.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1984</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1984</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/puzzlepanic</url>
    </game>
</games>
