<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor></alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Rommel: Battles for Tobruk&lt;/i&gt; is a turn-based strategy game with hexagonal cells. It is set during World War II and covers the battles between Rommel's Panzerarmee and the British 8th Army over Tobruk (Brevity, Battleaxe, Crusader and Gazala). The player either takes the role of one war party or battles against another fellow wargamer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;During each turn, both sides give detailed orders to their units which are then performed simultaneously. Order are assigned on the tactical map, but for planning there are also four strategic maps available which either show the terrain, Allied units, Axis units or all units. Additionally there are tables about corps (a list of all units), supply and airplanes. The simulation of the two latter are a focus of the game model. Of course there are also a number of other factors, including morale, unit capabilities, or, fatigue. A variety of options can be used to change the complexity of the game, including the AI level or if enemy units are visible. Supply and airplane effects can also be deactivated.</description>
        <developedBy>Worlds to Conquer, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Strategy/Tactics</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Rommel: Battles for Tobruk</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Game Designers' Workshop</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Worlds to Conquer, Inc.</developer>
                <publisher>Game Designers' Workshop</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1985</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1985</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/rommel-battles-for-tobruk</url>
    </game>
</games>
