<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor></alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/162604-sentinel-atari-8-bit-media.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>Nuclear missile silos all over Europe are launching!  Protect the USA by firing lasers from orbiting satellites to destroy both the missiles and the silos, as well as occasional bomber airplanes and alien UFOs, while protecting your cities as well as your satellites.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You control a crosshairs with the joystick and fire with the trigger; the closest satellite will fire a laser blast at your crosshairs and destroy whatever is underneath it, whether bomber, missile, or silo.  To complete a wave, destroy all missile silos.  You lose by either letting all your cities be destroyed or letting all your satellites be destroyed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sentinel plays basically like a two-screen Missile Command - on one screen is a map of Europe with several silos that launch missiles towards the top of the screen.  Your satellites are arrayed in space near the top of the screen.  Pressing a key on the keyboard will switch screens to a view of the other side of the world, the USA, where you can see your cities and any incoming missiles that you let get by on the other screen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dual screens adds an interesting twist to the Missile Command gameplay; you can see bombers and missiles take off in Europe and, when they leave the Europe screen, then appear on the USA screen.</description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Sentinel</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Intelligent Statements, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <publisher>Intelligent Statements, Inc.</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1982</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1982</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/382310-sentinel-atari-8-bit-screenshot-1-or-2-players.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/382311-sentinel-atari-8-bit-screenshot-stand-by-for-the-next-wave.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/382312-sentinel-atari-8-bit-screenshot-destroy-the-silos-and-their.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/382313-sentinel-atari-8-bit-screenshot-and-defend-your-cities.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/382314-sentinel-atari-8-bit-screenshot-watch-out-for-the-bomber.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/382315-sentinel-atari-8-bit-screenshot-bonus-points-at-end-of-round.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/382316-sentinel-atari-8-bit-screenshot-wave-2-more-silos-more-missiles.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/sentinel__</url>
    </game>
</games>
