<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Amstrad PCW, Apple II, Atari ST, Commodore 64, DOS, Macintosh, MSX, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/72235-silicon-dreams-atari-8-bit-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/72236-silicon-dreams-atari-8-bit-back-cover.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>This interactive fiction game is a trilogy of the Level 9's adventures &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=Snowball"&gt;Snowball&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="/game/return-to-eden"&gt;Return to Eden&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=Worm+in+Paradise"&gt;Worm in Paradise&lt;/a&gt;. These had previously been released for some but not all of these systems.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Silicon Dreams&lt;/i&gt; can be played as three separate games, but to obtain the maximum number of points, you must complete them in order (carrying your score from one adventure to the next). &lt;i&gt;Snowball&lt;/i&gt; has graphics for the first time, and the other two games have more graphics than before, and some longer text descriptions are added to all 3 games.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Snowball:&lt;/b&gt; As Kim Kimberley, your mission is to safeguard the colonization ship Snowball 9 and its passengers. When you are awakened prematurely from hibernation, you know something's wrong!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Return to Eden:&lt;/b&gt; Your objective is to get into the new city of Enoch, and stop the Eden robots from destroying Snowball 9.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Worm in Paradise:&lt;/b&gt; You have to find as much information about the city as possible, obtain money, and then become a member of the governing party of Eden.</description>
        <developedBy>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure, Compilation</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Silicon Dreams</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Rainbird Software</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <comments>Disk release</comments>
                <country> United Kingdom</country>
                <developer>Level 9 Computing, Ltd.</developer>
                <ean13>5 012439 006640</ean13>
                <publisher>Rainbird Software</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/377580-silicon-dreams-atari-8-bit-screenshot-game-selection-menu.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/silicon-dreams</url>
    </game>
</games>
