<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Apple II, Commodore 64, DOS | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Webster: The Word Game&lt;/i&gt; is a word recognition game. The object of the game is to fill in the missing letters of an incomplete word. On each round a word will appear at the top of the screen with several letters missing. The word will slowly begin moving towards the bottom of the screen and along the bottom of the screen is the complete alphabet. The player needs to select the letters that are missing from the word before time runs out and the word reaches the bottom of the screen. Successfully completing a word earns points, but if the word reaches the bottom of the screen then the player loses a life. The game ends when all five lives are lost. There are several skill levels available which affect the time limit for each word and the complexity of the word. The game includes over 700 words of varying length and difficulty. Scoring in the game is based on how many correct/incorrect letters are selected and whether or not hints are utilized.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In addition to the alphabet at the bottom of the screen are several asterisks; these represent hints. If more than one missing letter remains the player can choose a hint to fill in a missing letter in exchange for less points when the word is solved.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On more difficult skill levels, a demon word will occasionally appear; demon words are more difficult and move very fast compared to the other words. If the player fails when a demon word appears a life is not lost, however hints are not available. Also, if a demon word is not solved then the solution will not be revealed to the player unlike normal words. On skill level 7 (the toughest) there are also challenge rounds which consist entirely of demon words; in this case failing a demon word does cost a life. </description>
        <developedBy>Heuristic Software</developedBy>
        <genre>Educational</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Webster: The Word Game</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>CBS Software</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <developer>Heuristic Software</developer>
                <publisher>CBS Software</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1983</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1983</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533069-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-loading-cbs-presents.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533070-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533071-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-welcome-to-the.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533072-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-player-1-what.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533073-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-ready-to-begin.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533074-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-gameplay-the.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533075-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-some-words-are.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533076-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-hurry-running.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533077-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-the-answer-is.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533078-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-if-you-re-stumped.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533079-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-i-chose-a-d-apparently.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/533080-webster-the-word-game-atari-8-bit-screenshot-game-over.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/webster-the-word-game</url>
    </game>
</games>
