<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Apple II | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Whomper Stomper&lt;/i&gt; is an arcade-action game for 1 - 2 players. If chosen to play the 2-player mode the game is turn-based, as soon as a player loses a life the other player plays.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bill Bunion wanted nothing more but to enjoy a nice picnic lunch, but unfortunately ants foiled his picnic lunch. Bill Bunion got angry and eventually took it up to himself to stop the invasion of the ants.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As Bill Bunion it is your job to stomp the ants by using one of your foots (you can only see the foot anyways) and to stop them from reaching the picnic basket. If some ants come too close to the picnic basket, Artie, Bill's aardvark will suck them up. However, if too many ants come too close to the picnic basket they will carry it away and you will lose a life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Next to the ants there are also birds who will throw rocks at Bill's foot and in the easiest difficulty there are spikes that will hurt your foot later on, the spikes are already in the beginning on the medium and hard difficulty. If a bird hits Bill's foot or you stomp on a spike you will lose a life. After you have stomped a lot the foot will start to blink, which means it's aching and if not cured by stomping on an apple, which will also make your foot stomp faster, you will lose a life. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You start with 3 lives, lose all 3 and the game is over.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game also features speech.</description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Whomper Stomper</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Adventure International</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release>
                <country> United States</country>
                <publisher>Adventure International</publisher>
                <releaseDate>1984</releaseDate>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1984</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/atari-8-bit/whomper-stomper</url>
    </game>
</games>
