<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amstrad CPC, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>A knight called Clus d'Eledorf falls in love with princess Violeta. The jealous witch Saligia, herself in love with Clus, puts a curse on the lovers: the knight has to remain haunting the castle Burgenfels as a ghost, while the princess is forever lost in the woods.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Abracadabra&lt;/i&gt; is a Spanish text-adventure made with P.A.W. (Professional Adventure Writer), a popular Spectrum program. The parser is similar to the &lt;a href="/search/quick?company=Infocom"&gt;Infocom&lt;/a&gt; one: it supports most of the standard features of it at the time (chain commands, pronouns, adverbs, prepositions and adjectives, for example). The game is divided in two sections, with the second one loaded after the first is completed:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the first one, Clus has to break the curse and escape his prison. While in spectral form, the knight is destroyed if he leaves the castle. He can, however, roam freely through its halls to collect its objects and speak with its inhabitants. Burgenfels is a labyrinth with secret doors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the second load, a reincarnated Clus has to find princess Violeta, his lost love,  in the Greenwald forest.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        <developedBy>Odisea Software</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Abracadabra</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Proein S.L.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Spain</country>
                        <developer>Odisea Software</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Proein S.L.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1988</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1988</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/229091-abracadabra-msx-screenshot-loading-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/229093-abracadabra-msx-screenshot-game-start.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/229094-abracadabra-msx-screenshot-alcuino-the-monk.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/229178-abracadabra-msx-screenshot-guest-room.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/229179-abracadabra-msx-screenshot-stairflight.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/229180-abracadabra-msx-screenshot-corridor.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/abracadabra</url>
    </game>
</games>
