<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Apple II, Arcade, Atari 2600, ColecoVision, Commodore 64, Intellivision, Mattel Aquarius, NES, PC-8000, PC Booter, Sharp MZ-80K/700/800/1500, Sharp X1, TI-99/4A, Wii | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>You play as Chef Pepper and your goal is to make giant hamburgers while evil eggs, sausages and pickles chase you around the game area. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To properly make a hamburger you must assemble all of the ingredients together, dropping them from higher up onto the burger area below. To actually do this you have to let Chef Pepper step over every burger ingredient. As soon as an ingredient (a piece of lettuce for instance) has been stepped on, it will fall to the level below. Falling food will squish any enemy following you and will also &amp;quot;bump&amp;quot; any other ingredient below it farther down. Also, as an emergency defense against the enemy food, you can collect pepper shakers which will allow you to puff out a small pepper cloud that will momentarily stun enemies, allowing you to walk past them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Higher levels result in new level design, faster enemies and more ingredients to assemble.</description>
        <developedBy>Data East Corporation</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>BurgerTime</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Side view</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Dempa Shimbunsha</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Data East Corporation</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Dempa Shimbunsha</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/131530-burgertime-msx-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/131531-burgertime-msx-screenshot-score-and-item-points-overview.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/131532-burgertime-msx-screenshot-walk-through-the-maze-and-make-burgers.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/131533-burgertime-msx-screenshot-your-re-chased-by-an-egg-hot-dog.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/131534-burgertime-msx-screenshot-the-game-s-over.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/burgertime</url>
    </game>
</games>
