<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amstrad CPC, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Cobra's Arc is a curious conversational adventure in which the messages the computer send us play a fundamental role, but instead of replying to them directly, we must choose the action to do by pointing to the available icons of the actions menu, therefore this is what could be called an iconographic adventure. Also, you will find lots of places, personages and situations through the game, all of them surrounded in an atmosphere of fantasy and legend, so the action could take place in deserts, as well as inhospitable mountain ranges or mysterious walled cities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The plot of the game turns around a fabulous treasure, an immense amount of accumulated wealth during centuries by the priests of an old culture dedicated to the adoration of the god Cobra. According to the tradition, the temple where the priests jealously kept their jewels, diamonds and objects made with the most precious metals, was constructed on a ship, reason why it resisted the great deluge.
Now the fortune hunters have as obsession finding at all costs the palace of the god Cobra. But for it, they will have to fulfill two objectives: killing the prince Cobra and the wizard; once they do it, they will be ready to find so incredible treasure.</description>
        <developedBy>Dinamic Software</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Cobra's Arc</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Dinamic Software</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Spain</country>
                        <developer>Dinamic Software</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Dinamic Software</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/159657-cobra-s-arc-msx-screenshot-title-screen.gif</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/159658-cobra-s-arc-msx-screenshot-starting-out.gif</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/159659-cobra-s-arc-msx-screenshot-oops-wrong-way-to-go.gif</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/cobras-arc</url>
    </game>
</games>
