<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>A brave young warrior (whom the player names in the beginning of the game) has had his share of epic battles, so he decides to relax in him own house in the imperial capital city, dedicating himself to his other interests (read: women). However, one day a pretty young lady (whom the player also has to name) storms into his house, saying she has a message from the Emperor himself. A princess is missing, so our two heroes have to find her. And the hero also has to face some of his old foes...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Continental&lt;/i&gt; is a traditional Japanese RPG with a small party of heroes, top-down navigation, random turn-based battles viewed from first-person perspective, and no distinguishing characteristics but one: erotic scenes. There aren't as many here as in, for example, &lt;a href="/search/quick?gamegroup=Lightning+Warrior+Raidy"&gt; Lightning Warrior Raidy&lt;/a&gt; games, and they mostly occur in city brothels or after boss battles. The enemies, however, do look like pretty (although demonic) girls. Instead of undressing, though (as they do in Raidy games), they just shrink in size upon defeat.</description>
        <developedBy>Game Technopolis</developedBy>
        <genre>Role-Playing (RPG)</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Continental</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person, Top-down</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Game Technopolis</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Game Technopolis</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Game Technopolis</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1992</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1992</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/continental</url>
    </game>
</games>
