<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/307052-cosmic-psycho-msx-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/307053-cosmic-psycho-msx-back-cover.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>Kazuyuki is just an ordinary Japanese high-school student... or so he was before he saw a strange dream. In that dream, a girl was calling him from the outer space, imploring him to help her... The next day, Kazuyuki receives a strange phone call, after which he finds himself on board of a space ship! The girl from his dream appears and introduces herself: she is Marin, one of the members of a special squad that fights mysterious alien beings known as EX. Apparently, her message through time went to the wrong recipient, and now Kazuyuki is &amp;quot;stuck&amp;quot; in the end of the twenty-third century, reluctantly helping the beautiful ladies of the assault team to fight aliens - and perhaps engage in other, more pleasant activities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cosmic Psycho&lt;/i&gt; plays predominantly like a typical Japanese adventure, with verb/object commands that must be chosen from a menu repeatedly to trigger the next scene. However, at certain points the game turns into a side-scrolling shooter. Clad in a flying robotic suit, Kazuyuki must blast his way through a (usually very short) stage filled with regular enemies and bosses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game contains scenes with nudity and explicit sexual situations.</description>
        <developedBy>Cocktail Soft</developedBy>
        <genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Cosmic Psycho</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person, Side view</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Cocktail Soft</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Cocktail Soft</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Cocktail Soft</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>Sep 14, 1991</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>Sep 14, 1991</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/cosmic-psycho</url>
    </game>
</games>
