<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Acorn 32-bit, Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Atari ST, Commodore 64, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/169869-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/169868-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-back-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/169870-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-media.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>This multi-level action/adventure takes players back 40 years to find Professor K.K. Renegade, who predicts that a catastrophic asteroid is heading straight for earth. You're in charge of finding Professor Renegade. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Select one of the five most intrepid Adventurers from England, France, Germany, Japan, and the U.S. to spearhead the search. Professor Renegade was last seen in the unexplored region of the highest Tibetan ranges; an area populated by creatures and conditions of the professor's own design: venomous stone snakes, reptilian birds, and acid storms. Not only must your Adventurer survive these tests of courage, but he must and properly use such curious objects as spurs, a vacuum cleaner, and a unicycle.
Once you locate the professor and convince him to help, you'll need to help him construct an anti-asteroid deflector to prevent the destruction of earth. You must now search for high-tech tools such as an atomic pile, a 9-volt battery, and a bent coat hanger!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Use the joystick and the appropriate keys to maneuver the Adventurer across the landscape. You have 30 days to complete the mission. During the mission, the Adventurer collects various items (points are awarded for each). Some items serve little purpose; others are vital; and others only work in certain places. Only one item can be held at a time and it must be held to be used. Native bearers carry the items collected. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To look at what each bearer has, type 1 or 2 to scroll through the bearers. The Adventurer can exchange the item held (press S) with a bearer that is closest to him. Its trial and error time. Good luck. The game comes with cheats and a map for those that require a little help.</description>
        <developedBy>Teque Software Development Ltd.</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Cosmic Relief: Prof. Renegade to the Rescue</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Side view</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Grandslam Entertainments Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> United Kingdom</country>
                        <developer>Teque Software Development Ltd.</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Grandslam Entertainments Ltd.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1988</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1988</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440929-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-title.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440930-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-starting.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440931-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-i.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440932-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-these.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440933-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-well.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440934-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-i.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440935-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-i.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440936-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-hmm.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440937-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-i.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440938-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-this.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440939-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-i.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/440940-cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue-msx-screenshot-the.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/cosmic-relief-prof-renegade-to-the-rescue</url>
    </game>
</games>
