<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>FM Towns, PC-88, PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;D.P.S&lt;/i&gt; is a collection of three short scenarios, which are unrelated to each other story-wise and can be played separately. Those scenarios are presented as cartridges played on a fictional console named &lt;i&gt;Dream Program System&lt;/i&gt;. Each scenario allows the player to choose between two different protagonists, or two different personalities for the protagonist. All of the scenarios feature nudity and/or sexual situations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scenarios in this game include:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; A medieval fantasy tale entitled &lt;i&gt;Princess Fantasy&lt;/i&gt;, in which the player controls a knight who accompanies a princess on a journey. Depending on the personality choice, the knight can either be brave and compassionate, or cynically take advantage of the helpless girl.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A typical &amp;quot;naughty doctor&amp;quot; story, in which the player - as either male or female school doctor - has to &amp;quot;examine&amp;quot; young and pretty female patients, trying not to scare them away by employing too direct methods.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt; An encounter between a famous female pop idol and her fan (also female), which leads to a bizarre sexual experience. The player can choose to control the events from the point of view of either the star or the fan.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;The gameplay is essentially that of a visual novel. At almost every screen, the player is given a number of choices, which correspond to answers or actions, according to the situation. Some choices are required to trigger the next event and advance in the game, others are &amp;quot;neutral&amp;quot;, having no effect on the progress, while a few are considered &amp;quot;bad&amp;quot; by the game, leading to Game Over. Scenes, dialogue choices, and story events may vary slightly or significantly, depending on the choice of character in the beginning of a scenario.</description>
        <developedBy>Alice Soft</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>D.P.S: Dream Program System</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Alice Soft</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Alice Soft</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Alice Soft</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>Apr 15, 1990</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>Apr 15, 1990</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/dps-dream-program-system</url>
    </game>
</games>
