<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>FM Towns, PC-88, PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;D.P.S. SG Set 2&lt;/i&gt; is the third entry in the &lt;a href="/search/quick?gamegroup=D%2eP%2eS%2e"&gt; D.P.S./Dream Program System series&lt;/a&gt;. Like the other &lt;i&gt;D.P.S.&lt;/i&gt; games, it is a collection of three short scenarios, which are unrelated to each other story-wise and can be played separately. Those scenarios are presented as cartridges played on a fictional console named &lt;i&gt;Dream Program System&lt;/i&gt;. Each scenario allows the player to choose between two different protagonists, or two different personalities for the protagonist. All of the scenarios feature nudity and/or sexual situations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scenarios in this game include:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;A horror story entitled &lt;i&gt;Antique House&lt;/i&gt;, in which a young couple is trapped at night in a secluded haunted mansion, possessed by monsters. The player can choose the personality of the female character before beginning, influencing the story with this choice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;A modern-day story without any supernatural elements, entitled &lt;i&gt;Red Night&lt;/i&gt;. The protagonist is a man who finds himself in a hotel when a fire starts. Trying to escape, he enters a room occupied by a prostitute. The following events evolve slightly differently, depending on the personality choice made by the player before the start of the game.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;A sequel to the second episode of the &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=dream+program+scenario"&gt; first D.P.S. game&lt;/a&gt;. Once again, the player chooses either the male doctor Katsuki or the female doctor Katsumi whose goal is to seduce the patient, the cute school girl Yumiko.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The gameplay is the same as in other &lt;i&gt;D.P.S.&lt;/i&gt; games. At almost every screen, the player is given a number of choices, which correspond to answers or actions, according to the situation. Some choices are required to trigger the next event and advance in the game, others are &amp;quot;neutral&amp;quot;, having no effect on the progress, while a few are considered &amp;quot;bad&amp;quot; by the game, leading to Game Over. Scenes, dialogue choices, and story events may vary slightly or significantly, depending on the choice of character in the beginning of a scenario.</description>
        <developedBy>Alice Soft</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Dream Program System SG Set 2</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Alice Soft</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Alice Soft</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Alice Soft</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>May 15, 1991</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>May 15, 1991</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/dream-program-system-sg-set-2</url>
    </game>
</games>
