<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Commodore 16, Plus/4, Commodore 64, Electron, VIC-20, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Flight Path 737&lt;/i&gt; is a flight simulator or as the cover says an &amp;quot;advanced pilot trainer&amp;quot;. The player is the pilot of a jet airliner and his task is to take of from an airport, climb over the mountains that surrounds it and then land safely on an airfield in the valleys below. The player only gets one chance as there is only enough fuel for one landing. The game is played from a first person perspective and the screen is split into two parts: a landscape view at the top and the instrument panel below. The instrument panel shows all the information that is needed such as altitude, speed and artificial horizon. The game can be played on six different skill levels. Each level adds more complexity to the task. On the first level the mountains are 5000 ft. high and the runway is three miles long but for each level the mountains get higher and the runway gets shorter. On the most difficult level the mountains are 9200 ft. and the runway is only 1.5 miles. Each level also adds more tasks that have to be taken care. On level 2 the engine can catch fire, while level 3 require smoother landing. Level 4 to 6 add crosswinds and require reverse thrust when landing. </description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Simulation</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Flight Path 737</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Anirog Software Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> United Kingdom</country>
                        <developer></developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Anirog Software Ltd.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1985</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1985</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/557157-flight-path-737-msx-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/557158-flight-path-737-msx-screenshot-level-selection.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/557159-flight-path-737-msx-screenshot-briefing.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/557160-flight-path-737-msx-screenshot-on-the-runway.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/flight-path-737</url>
    </game>
</games>
