<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>iPhone, SEGA Master System | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/80241-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/80242-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-back-cover.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>In this game, you play Kelesis, a warrior who is sent to seek out Golvellius and rescue the beautiful Princess Rena. But in order to find him, you must defeat seven of his fiercest demons that were sent to stop you. These demons are found in caves throughout the valley floor, but in order to access these caves, you need to defeat some of the wild beasts that are scattered throughout the valley. When you kill these beasts, you will receive some gold, but when you are hit by these beasts, your energy will be lost. Some caves will appear when certain objects are struck with your sword. In some caves,you will find fairies, sorceresses, and wise women who will help you in many ways be increasing gold, giving you life potions, and restoring your energy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There is a password save feature in this game. At the beginning of each area, you can enter a cave where a woman tells you what the password is, but if you die in the course of your quest, the password will already be revealed. By entering this password, you will be able to begin the game from the opening of the valley (if you get that far) with all your possessions intact.</description>
        <developedBy>Compile</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Golvellius: Valley of Doom</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Side view, Top-down</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Compile</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Compile</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Compile</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1987</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1987</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/132088-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/132089-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-screenshot-begin-of-level-2.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/132090-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-screenshot-you-got-to-search.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/132091-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-screenshot-here-s-an-item.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/132092-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-screenshot-start-level-one.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/132093-golvellius-valley-of-doom-msx-screenshot-kill-the-creature.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/golvellius-valley-of-doom</url>
    </game>
</games>
