<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>FM Towns, PC-88, PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Gengorou Imai is a 19-year old lad who wants to have a simple life, his only passion being young pretty women. He stays in a boarding house in the country, enjoying the quiet life, the sea, the beach, and the abundance of those he likes most... So all goes well, until one of the guests who was staying at the boarding house is killed. Not entirely trusting the police, the owner of the boarding house asks Gen to look into this. Gen knows that the deceased was having a relationship with the owner's daughter. The young man begins his investigation, saying good-bye to quiet life - but not to the seductive young female tenants of the boarding house...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hoshi no Suna Monogatari&lt;/i&gt; is the first in the &lt;a href="/search/quick?gamegroup=hoshi+no+suna"&gt; series&lt;/a&gt; of adult detective/mystery adventures by &lt;a href="/search/quick?company=D%2eO%2e"&gt; D.O.&lt;/a&gt;. The game world is composed of still screens viewed from first-person perspective; navigation is done by selecting locations from a menu. At every screen, a full list of commands is available, from the standard &amp;quot;Look&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Talk&amp;quot; to the more specific &amp;quot;Kiss&amp;quot;, as well as &amp;quot;Ask&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Use Item&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;Show Item&amp;quot;. Advancing in the game usually means investigating the locations, talking to everyone, asking the right person about the right topic, and showing the right person the right item. </description>
        <developedBy>D.O. Corp.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Hoshi no Suna Monogatari</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>D.O. Corp.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>D.O. Corp.</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>D.O. Corp.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1990</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1990</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/hoshi-no-suna-monogatari</url>
    </game>
</games>
