<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>FM Towns, PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Christmas 1999: an atomic war has begun. Most of the Earth's population was wiped out. Only a few millions remained. Three years have passed, and the leading scientists of the world started working on a project to re-build the planet. But not everyone agreed with them; some people were profiting from the chaos and devastation. Those people founded a terrorist organization called &amp;quot;Black Widow&amp;quot;, with the goal to impede the project. To counter that, project leaders hired a group of five trained agents known as &amp;quot;Snipers&amp;quot;. The protagonist of the game is a Class-A sniper named Joe, who is about to be trained by his colleagues...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;L Elle&lt;/i&gt; is a point-and-click adventure in Japanese style (no puzzles). The interaction with the environment is performed by moving the mouse cursor around; when it is possible to interact with an object, the cursor turns into a command icon (look, talk, push, take, etc., depending on the situation). The navigation is performed by selecting locations from a menu. The player advances by examining objects, talking to people, and unlocking new locations.</description>
        <developedBy>Elf Co., Ltd.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>L Elle</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Elf Co., Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Elf Co., Ltd.</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Elf Co., Ltd.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>Feb 17, 1992</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>Feb 17, 1992</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/l-elle</url>
    </game>
</games>
