<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Atari ST, Commodore 64, DOS, PC-98, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>In &lt;i&gt;Laser Squad&lt;/i&gt; you control a group of space marine-like soldiers (and the occasional cyborg). Before taking them into battle (viewed from above and progressing in turns), you must buy them weapons and armour with a predetermined amount of credits, taking into account the individual abilities of your squad. Unlike X-COM, the soldiers do not gain experience over time.&lt;br&gt;
The game also features a two player hotseat multiplayer option.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Initial ZX Spectrum release (and C64 &amp;amp; Amstrad CPC cassette tape releases) had three missions:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;1: &lt;i&gt;The Assassins&lt;/i&gt; - where you must face down Sterner Regnix and his guards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2: &lt;i&gt;Moonbase Assault&lt;/i&gt; - which challenges you to destroy the OmniCorp database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3: &lt;i&gt;Rescue from the Mines&lt;/i&gt; - eschew violence in favour of a rescue mission&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
Two more scenarios were available via mail order, later releases by Blade Software and subsequent ports already included them:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;4: &lt;i&gt;The Cyber Hordes&lt;/i&gt; - defend a rebel station and its seven stabilizer cores from an advancing imperial droid invasion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5: &lt;i&gt;Paradise Valley&lt;/i&gt; - following the destruction of the stabilizer cores, escape from the colony with the device containing blueprints for advanced rebel starfighter&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Two additional missions were released with mail order &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=Laser+Squad+Kit"&gt;expansion kit&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
        <developedBy>Target Games Limited</developedBy>
        <genre>Strategy/Tactics</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Laser Squad</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Top-down</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Blade Software Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Italy</country>
                        <developer>Target Games Limited</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Blade Software Ltd.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1988</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1988</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/laser-squad</url>
    </game>
</games>
