<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amstrad CPC, Amstrad PCW, DOS, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&amp;quot;Los lnhumanos&amp;quot; is a game in which our objective will be to rescue the girl who has been kidnapped by another enemy group called &amp;quot;Los Rokopiedras&amp;quot;. Besides capturing our beloved, they have also committed an excess which is what really did upset Zufuru, the inhuman protagonist of this history: they have destroyed his dear Simca 1000, a unique car, full of memories of our friend.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And, as this history occurs in the city of the skyscrapers, the distant New York, Zufuru will have to cross the famous Central Park in order to find the resting four pieces of his little car. Only when all of them would be on his possession he will be able to accede to the Empire State, the second level of the game and where his beloved is located.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For the most curious, this game debts its name to a Spanish pop music group which had quite succes during the eighties, period in which they produced some of the most danced songs on the Spanish youthful and universitary circles, that's also why you can listen to some of their most famous songs during the game, as well as seeing their mascot on the game.</description>
        <developedBy>Delta Software, S.L.</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc>Licensed</misc>
        <name>Los Inhumanos</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>3rd-person [DEPRECATED]</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Delta Software, S.L.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Spain</country>
                        <developer>Delta Software, S.L.</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Delta Software, S.L.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1990</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1990</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/los-inhumanos</url>
    </game>
</games>
