<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amstrad CPC, Commodore 64, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;MASK II&lt;/i&gt; is a single player side scrolling shoot-em-up and is the second game in the M.A.S.K (Mobile Armored Strike Kommand) series that was based on a TV series / comic / toy license of the mid 1980's. 
The M.A.S.K organisation is once again battling the bad guys in the form of the criminal V.E.N.O.M. (Vicious Evil Network of Mayhem) organisation in their transformer like vehicles. This game consists of three missions:&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Mission one is about destroying an oil refinery that V.E.N.O.M. have set up in the middle east as part of their bid to control oil prices.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mission two starts with a tribe in the jungle who worship a fabulous ruby. V.E.N.O.M. have stolen the ruby and are using it in a laser ray gun. It is M.A.S.K.'s job to destroy the laser and to return the ruby to the tribe in the jungle.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mission three sees V.E.N.O.M. holding the president of the P.N.A. hostage and the mission is to rescue him and get him to the summit talks in time to sign a peace treaty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;In each mission the player starts by selecting three M.A.S.K. agents. These should be chosen with care as the agents drive different vehicles and completing each mission will require having the right agent and their vehicle at your disposal. 
Once into the game the player has five lives with which they must complete their mission by driving, flying and hydro-planing across the varied terrain, battling V.E.N.O.M. vehicles, overcoming obstacles, and picking up power-ups along the way.</description>
        <developedBy>Gremlin Graphics Software Limited</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc>Licensed</misc>
        <name>MASK Two Two</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Side view</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Gremlin Graphics Software Limited</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> United Kingdom</country>
                        <developer>Gremlin Graphics Software Limited</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Gremlin Graphics Software Limited</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1987</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1987</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/530797-mask-two-two-msx-screenshot-loading-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/530798-mask-two-two-msx-screenshot-alert.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/530799-mask-two-two-msx-screenshot-mission-briefing.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/530800-mask-two-two-msx-screenshot-choose-your-team.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/530801-mask-two-two-msx-screenshot-i-chose-matt-trakker.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/mask-two-two</url>
    </game>
</games>
