<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>FM Towns, PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>It happened long time ago, when mankind possessed the secrets of magic. One time, when a comet was approaching the Earth, a young woman gave birth to a baby. He was taken into the nearby village and grew up there. But he knew he was different from other children: he could not use magic, and on his hand there was a little star. He believed that he was cursed, and so did many people in his village. He learns that the ominous cave in the Northern Mountain might hold the answers to his questions. He embarks on this journey, determined to find out the identity of his father and his true role in the world.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mirage&lt;/i&gt; is essentially a dungeon crawler: the biggest portion of the game is spent navigating pseudo-3D maze-like dungeons (auto-mapped), fighting random enemies in turn-based combat. The hero is accompanied by another character, and both participate in combat. With time the hero and his companion learn magical spells. Dungeons also contain areas where weapons and items can be purchased.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game contains scenes with nudity and erotic images (though nothing &amp;quot;hardcore&amp;quot;). Many of the random enemies are pretty female demons, who disrobe when defeated.</description>
        <developedBy>Discovery</developedBy>
        <genre>Role-Playing (RPG)</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Mirage</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Discovery</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Discovery</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Discovery</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1992</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1992</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/mirage_</url>
    </game>
</games>
