<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>PC-88, PC-98, Sharp X68000 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Misty Vol.4&lt;/i&gt; is a detective mystery adventure game set in modern-day Japan and starring the young private investigator RyÅ« Kamishiro. The game consists of five unrelated cases that can be accessed in any order from the main menu. These cases range from seemingly mundane matters to thefts, mysterious disappearances and murder investigations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This volume contains the following cases: &lt;i&gt;Returning to the Sky&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Time of Atonement&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Moon Walk&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Alibi in the Clock&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Photo in the Nothingness&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game largely consists of text-only descriptions and dialogues, though some locations and scenes are accompanied by sparse black and white digitized photos. The player is presented with a text list of locations in the city, and much of the gameplay is dedicated to repeatedly visiting them, searching areas and questioning suspects. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The player is awarded points depending on the efficiency and the speed of the investigation. It is possible to accuse suspects and attempt to solve the case at any point, though doing so without sufficient evidence will result in failure. The game saves the progress automatically; it is possible to restart the investigation only by deleting the save file.</description>
        <developedBy>Data West</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Misty Vol.4</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Data West</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Data West</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Data West</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>Jul 25, 1990</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>Jul 25, 1990</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/misty-vol4</url>
    </game>
</games>
