<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor></alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/78562-night-city-msx-front-cover.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>You have been out partying, but when you arrive at your house, you notice that you've lost your keys. Furthermore, you've promised to be home at 3:00, and your watch is missing too. Suddenly, you are approached by a police officer who asks for your ID, and you can't seem to find that either. You run from the police, into the night city. You must find your identification, your watch and your keys before 3 o'clock!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In this arcade adventure game, you run through the streets of the bleak city infested with rats, angry policemen and evil ghosts, looking for your belongings. The streets scroll from left to right, and going up or down takes you to another street. You've got a gun with which to kill the enemies, but they respawn quickly, and when you've run out of bullets, you can only rely on kicks, or try to avoid the ghosts' rays by ducking. At some spots, you can replenish your energy and ammunition.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Finding your watch will let you know how much time you have left, the ID papers will stop the police from bothering you, and finding all your keys will allow you to get home and end the game. The action is fast, and so is the in-game music accompanying the suitably toned-downed graphics of Night City.</description>
        <developedBy>Yermani Soft</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Night City</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Side view</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Yermani Soft</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Worldwide</country>
                        <developer>Yermani Soft</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Yermani Soft</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>Dec 21, 2006</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>Dec 21, 2006</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/206178-night-city-msx-screenshot-view-of-the-night-city.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/206179-night-city-msx-screenshot-you-start-out-in-this-unfriendly.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/206180-night-city-msx-screenshot-you-can-go-up-to-the-next-street.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/206181-night-city-msx-screenshot-found-your-watch.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/night-city</url>
    </game>
</games>
