<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor></alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&amp;quot;O Ogro&amp;quot; is a brazilian maze game for the MSX computers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In it you control a small round character and you must kill all enemies in each maze. Some enemies require only one shot to die, and others when shot will transform into another monster. When an enemy dies it becomes a crystal which will earn you points if you take it. When you have defeated all enemies in the maze, you must return to your house at the top-left corner of the maze. If you take too long to defeat the enemies, a &amp;quot;walking flame&amp;quot; will appear and chase you. Also, you have a limited amount of &amp;quot;air&amp;quot; which gradually decreases as time passes. If you run out of air you lose a life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If your character is captured by an enemy, a &amp;quot;copy&amp;quot; of it will appear inside a small &amp;quot;cage&amp;quot; at the top-right corner of the maze, and you will restart the level. Sometimes a key will appear, and if you take it, you will be able to set free the &amp;quot;copy&amp;quot; of the character and will earn an extra life (that is, you will get that life back).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After a couple of levels a bonus level will appear. In it you must catch all items within a time limit. If you manage to catch all items, you will earn bonus points.</description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>O Ogro</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>3rd-person [DEPRECATED]</perspective>
        <publishedBy></publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info/>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1988</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498718-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-loading-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498719-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-title-screen-where-are-the-credits.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498720-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-first-level.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498721-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-monsters-become-crystals-once-you-kill.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498722-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-second-level.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498723-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-bonus-level-catch-all-rings-and-you.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498724-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-after-catching-all-items-in-the-bonus.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498725-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-third-level.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/498726-o-ogro-msx-screenshot-final-de-jogo-game-over.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/o-ogro</url>
    </game>
</games>
