<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>PC-88, PC-98 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Hiroyuki Kitahara was leading a rather ordinary life in a quiet Japanese town, and decided one day to take a stroll at night, enjoying the picturesque landscape. All of a sudden, a horrifying monster appeared right in front of him. Kitahara wakes up in the hospital and tries to convince the doctors that he was not hallucinating. Teaming up with a young female journalist, Kitahara begins to explore the city, searching for clues to solve the mystery and seeking meeting with onryÅ - ghosts of people who were wronged in their lifetime and who are back for revenge.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;OnryÅ Senki&lt;/i&gt; is a Japanese-style adventure game. There are no puzzles and no items to pick up or manipulate. Interaction with the environment is done by selecting commands from a menu. Four standard commands (Look, Listen, Think, and Go) appear on most screens and sometimes lead to sub-menus with objects. For the most part the player is free to visit various locations in the town in any order. At the protagonist's home it is also possible to use the computer to review people's dossiers and information.</description>
        <developedBy>Soft Studio Wing</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Onryō Senki</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Soft Studio Wing</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Soft Studio Wing</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Soft Studio Wing</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>Jun 01, 1989</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>Jun 01, 1989</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/onry-senki</url>
    </game>
</games>
