<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>NES | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Players take control of Demon Kogure, a member of the real life Japanese heavy metal band Seikima-II. He is on a mission to rescue his fellow &amp;quot;demon&amp;quot; bandmates who have been captured and imprisoned by the God Zeus.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game is broken up into four zones that are composed of eight areas each. In each area players have to collect all the visible items laying around to complete that area. Once all the items are collected in the seven areas of a zone, players can then enter the eighth area where they will find one of their bandmates locked inside a cage. After collecting all the items in the eighth zone, the player has to open the lids of three caskets. After the last casket is opened it will produce a key, which can then be used to release the locked up bandmate. While collecting all the visible items, players will be continuously attacked by enemies that they can either try to jump and dodge or shoot their projectile weapon at them. Getting hit by an enemy will decrease the players life, which is already constantly draining.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of the items the player collects are moneybags. Collected moneybags earn the player money which can in turn be spent at the various shops found throughout the game. Shops sell life potions, stronger weapons, and also musical instruments for each band member.</description>
        <developedBy>ISCO, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc>Licensed</misc>
        <name>Seikima II: Akuma no Gyakushū</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Side view</perspective>
        <publishedBy>CBS/Sony Group Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>ISCO, Inc.</developer>
                        <ean13>4 901780 064885</ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>CBS/Sony Group Inc.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1987</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1987</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/seikima-ii-akuma-no-gyakush</url>
    </game>
</games>
