<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>FM-7, PC-88, PC-98, Sharp X1 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Despite its name (a misspelling of &lt;i&gt;Azteca&lt;/i&gt;), the story of &lt;i&gt;TaiyÅ no Shinden: Asteka II&lt;/i&gt; is dedicated to the Maya people, indigenous inhabitants of Southern Mexico and Central America, rather than the Aztecs. The player controls a nameless adventurer who searches for the Sun Key, a mysterious ancient artifact which can unlock the secrets of the Mayan civilization.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;TaiyÅ no Shinden: Asteka II&lt;/i&gt; is an adventure game which takes place in the ruins of the ancient city Chichen Itza on the Yucatan peninsula in Mexico. There is a top-down overworld on which the player can physically navigate the protagonist, entering temples and other locations. In such locations, the view switches to first-person perspective. The player interacts with the environment by selecting various verb commands (&amp;quot;Look&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Take&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Use&amp;quot;, etc.), represented by icons, from a menu, and combining them with objects on the screen. In spite of its Japanese origins, the game features inventory item usage and puzzle-solving, which are more typical of Western-style adventures.</description>
        <developedBy>Nihon Falcom Corp.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Taiyō no Shinden</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>1st-person, Top-down</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Tokyo Shoseki Co., Ltd.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Japan</country>
                        <developer>Nihon Falcom Corp.</developer>
                        <ean13>4 961355 677025</ean13>
                        <ported>ZAP Corporation</ported>
                        <publisher>Tokyo Shoseki Co., Ltd.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>Dec 10, 1987</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>Dec 10, 1987</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/taiy-no-shinden</url>
    </game>
</games>
