<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Amiga, Amstrad CPC, Arcade, Atari ST, Commodore 64, ZX Spectrum | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Time Scanner&lt;/i&gt; is a pinball game. As usual, the goal is to keep the ball in the game by bouncing it back with the paddles. Hitting bumpers and other obstacles rewards points and completing a table requires mastering certain objectives which depend on the table on hand. Every table is divided into twp parts with their own paddles: the game only scrolls if the ball goes down. The four tables are:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Volcano: The winning condition is to spell the table's name by using the associated volcano lanes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruins: In the middle of the table there is a &amp;quot;collect ball&amp;quot; hole. If all targets were hit and two balls were collected in the hole, a special fire ball is set loose. The stage is won when bringing this ball into the hole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saqqarah: This pyramid themed table also required spelling a name by knocking down targets and hitting a special hole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The last table introduces &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=Breakout"&gt;Breakout&lt;/a&gt; elements: the player needs to hit blocks to vaporize them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
The first three tables can be freely selected and the last one is unlocked by beating the other three.</description>
        <developedBy>SEGA Enterprises Ltd.</developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Time Scanner</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Top-down</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Activision, Inc.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> United Kingdom</country>
                        <developer>SEGA Enterprises Ltd.</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported>Spidersoft Limited</ported>
                        <publisher>Activision, Inc.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1989</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1989</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/time-scanner</url>
    </game>
</games>
