<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Commodore 64 | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>&lt;i&gt;Topografie Europa&lt;/i&gt; is an educational computer game which teaches the locations and names of cities, towns, regions and rivers of Europe.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are 3 modes, which are Opzoeken (Look up), Overhoring (Quiz), Het Stedenspel (The City Game). The game contains a mid 1980s map of Europe, as evidenced by countries such as East Germany, West Germany, Yugoslavia and Czechoslovakia. It contains many names and locations of cities, rivers and seas.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In Look Up mode you can type the name of a city or sea and the game will point it out on the map. In Quiz mode, the game will point a randomly selected place and the player must type in the name on time. The helicopter mode is the main part of the game. The player controls a helicopter and must fly to a randomly selected city or location before the time runs out. When the helicopter is close enough to the target city or location, it will turn into a pulsating red dot.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Additionally there is an information browser which shows data per country or a bar graph comparing all countries. The data includes the area in square kilometers, population, agriculture, industry and service industry data.</description>
        <developedBy>Radarsoft BV</developedBy>
        <genre>Educational</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Topografie Europa</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Top-down</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Radarsoft BV</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> The Netherlands</country>
                        <developer>Radarsoft BV</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Radarsoft BV</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots/>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/topografie-europa</url>
    </game>
</games>
