<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor>Apple II, Atari ST, Commodore 64, DOS | Combined View</alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers/>
        <description>Jim Hawkins is a young boy working on &amp;quot;Admiral Benbow&amp;quot;, his parent's inn. One day a sea captain named Billy Bones takes a room at the inn and stays for several months. A blind man called Pew arrives and shows something to Billy that gives him a heart attack. Jim witnesses everything and runs to aid the captain, who tells him about his sea chest and his relationship with Captain Flint, a famous pirate. After he dies Jim grabs the key dangling from the corpse and opens the dead captain's chest to collect the last payment. He finds a packet inside, and decides to take it to two aristocratic acquaintances of his, Dr. Livesey and Squire John Trelawney. They discover a diary and a treasure map, and decide to travel to the island in search of the booty.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Treasure Island&lt;/i&gt; is a text adventure, an adaptation of the classic 1883 novel of the same name by &lt;a href="/developer/sheet/view/developerId,222329/"&gt;Robert Louis Stevenson&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the book, the game is written in a second-person perspective. Otherwise, it follows the original plot closely: the player assumes the role of Jim Hawkins, and has to perform the same actions as the character in the novel. This leads to a more claustrophobic design, as players without knowledge of the book have to guess what to do next. To help alleviate that problem, other characters act as some sort of built-in hint system. The player can ask them about anything and they will provide clues when these are available. The parser accepts most of &lt;a href="http://www.mobygames.com/company/infocom"&gt;Infocom&lt;/a&gt;'s standard features like pronouns and chain commands. </description>
        <developedBy>Byron Preiss Video Productions, Inc.</developedBy>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Treasure Island</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective></perspective>
        <publishedBy>Idealogic S.A.</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> Spain</country>
                        <developer>Byron Preiss Video Productions, Inc.</developer>
                        <ean13></ean13>
                        <ported>Telarium Corp.</ported>
                        <publisher>Idealogic S.A.</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232184-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232185-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-demo-jolly-roger.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232186-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-demo-men-with-low-moral-fiber.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232187-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-demo-long-john-silver-and-ben.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232188-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-demo-friends.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232189-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-billy-bones.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232190-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-rum-tankards.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/232191-treasure-island-msx-screenshot-goofy-credits-screen.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/treasure-island_</url>
    </game>
</games>
