<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<games>
    <game>
        <alsoFor></alsoFor>
        <country></country>
        <covers>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/82423-vestron-msx-front-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/82424-vestron-msx-back-cover.jpg</cover>
            <cover>/images/covers/l/82425-vestron-msx-media.jpg</cover>
        </covers>
        <description>In the intergalactic war, the Amstradian empire has taken over most of the known universe. Earth is still putting up some resistance, but is running out of natural resources. It is discovered that the old mining planet of Vestron contains a special kind of crystals which can be substituted for oil. Retrieving these crystals is imperative for Earth to be able to keep on fighting, so you are sent alone to recover the energy source from Vestron.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The game is made up of two different screens. On the static screen, you fly around in your space suit right above the surface, where crystals can be found. Pick up the crystals while avoiding the Amstradians, which luckily move back and forth in preset patterns. If you run the risk of a collision, you can press the space bar to activate your &lt;a href="/search/quick?game=Asteroids"&gt;Asteroids&lt;/a&gt; style emergency teleport. This feature should be used only as a last-ditch effort, since you could just as well teleport straight into another enemy. You can travel up, left and right, to travel down you just let gravity do its job.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After having retrieved the crystals on the static screen, you progress to a scrolling screen which takes you to the next crystal site. In order to get through this screen, you must avoid all the Amstradian ships which attack in a kamikaze fashion. Reflexes are a requirement, since the enemies move very quickly and track all your movements.</description>
        <developedBy></developedBy>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <misc></misc>
        <name>Vestron</name>
        <nonSport></nonSport>
        <perspective>Side view</perspective>
        <publishedBy>Players Software</publishedBy>
        <releases>
            <release system="MSX">
                <releases-info>
                    <releases>
                        <comments></comments>
                        <country> United Kingdom</country>
                        <developer></developer>
                        <ean13>5 013728 000356</ean13>
                        <ported></ported>
                        <publisher>Players Software</publisher>
                        <releaseDate>1986</releaseDate>
                    </releases>
                </releases-info>
            </release>
        </releases>
        <releaseDate></releaseDate>
        <released>1986</released>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/213846-vestron-msx-screenshot-title-screen.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/213847-vestron-msx-screenshot-avoid-the-flying-things-pick-up-the.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/213848-vestron-msx-screenshot-you-touched-an-enemy.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/213850-vestron-msx-screenshot-the-side-scrolling-screen-is-vehemently.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/213849-vestron-msx-screenshot-bang.png</shot>
            <shot>/images/shots/l/213851-vestron-msx-screenshot-game-over.png</shot>
        </screenshots>
        <sport></sport>
        <theme></theme>
        <url>http://www.mobygames.com//game/msx/vestron</url>
    </game>
</games>
