<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>16 then 256</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>Socket for a 80287 math coprocessor</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Intel 80286 (8086 in the Kaypro PC)</cpu>
        <description>
Kaypro's loyalty to customers was legendary.  In fact, its refusal to abandon CP/M users dangerously delayed its adoption of the DOS Operating System.  Nevertheless, it eventually acceded and was one of the last US manufacturer to introduce a PC compatible system simply named the Kaypro PC

It was most affordable package in the IBM-compatible world including a CAD-capable Samsung monitor and ATI video card capable of Hercules graphics, CGA color, and CGA color emulation on a monochrome monitor.  The entry machine was faster than its IBM PC-XT rival.  Typically, it was a rugged, dependable desktop PC that immediately out-classed IBM in additional areas by including larger and faster standard hard drives, generous free software combinations, and top-flight ring-bound user documentation.

Still in 1985 came the Kaypro 286i, the very first available PC/AT-compatible system, faster at the same clock speed than the IBM model, it was quickly revised with Intel's latest chip, the 8MHz 286, running over 30% faster than IBM's offering.  

Kaypro engineered its own high quality motherboards and introduced upgradable processors in desktop PCs, mounting the computers microprocessor on a replaceable expansion card instead of on the expensive motherboard; thus facilitating easy, lower-cost replacement of the processor.

Kaypro pioneered advanced memory usage, managing to squeeze out an additional 128 KB in the first megabyte of standard DOS memory, thus giving users access to the full 728 KB of DOS memory instead of the 640 KB allowed on other systems.  This extra memory was available as a fast virtual drive for active data files, greatly speeding computing performance.

In a time when full IBM-compatibility was more often marketing hype than hard reality, Kaypro went beyond the rest of the industry and backed its PCs with the only money-back guarantee of FULL IBM-compatibility.  The PC was so good that Kaypro even guaranteed to buy a dissatisfied customer a replacement from IBM if they desired.

Spec. board is for the 286i version - Thanks to Dennis for the pictures.
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Hercules graphics (720 x 348) or CGA (640 x 200)</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Kaypro_Desktop_System_s1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Standard PC-XT - 84 key</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Kaypro</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 1.2 MB 5.25'' FDD, optional 20 then 40 MB HDD (2 x 360 KB 5.25'' FDD in the Kaypro PC)</media>
        <name>PC &amp;amp; 286i</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals>8 ISA slots</peripherals>
        <ports>1 X Parallel, 2 x Serial, Composite video</ports>
        <power>Built-in switching PSU</power>
        <price>From $4500 in 1985 - $2995 in 1987</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>512 KB up to 768 KB</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;COMPLETE SYSTEM&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;PC-XT monochrome version with original boxes - not in great shape - Manuals and software.&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Kaypro_Desktop_WithBoxes_s1.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>52 (W) x 39 (D) x 16 (H) cm (main unit)</size>
        <sound>Built-in one channel speaker</sound>
        <speed>6 then 8 then 12 MHz (1987)</speed>
        <text>40 or 80 columns x 25 lines</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram>16 KB</vram>
        <year>1985</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
