<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>None</coprocessor>
        <cpu>55,000 vacuum tubes in each unit</cpu>
        <description>
The AN/FSQ-7 was by far the largest computer ever built, and is 
expected to hold that record. It consisted of two complete Whirlwind II computers installed in a 4-story building (See the impressive diagram in the 'More Pictures' section).

Each AN/FSQ supported more than 100 users. IBM had about 60 employees 
at each site for round-the-clock maintenance.
Keeping one unit operating and one on hot standby (to allow for 
switchover when vacuum tubes failed) resulted in better than 99% 
uptime. The roles of the two units were reversed at regular 
intervals, allowing diagnostics and maintenance to be carried 
out on the standby unit.

There were usually several hundred tube failures each day, 
replaced by workers racing up and down the tube racks with 
shopping carts full of replacements. Automated tests run by the 
computer itself would cycle the voltage to the tube racks down 
and back up to induce marginal tubes to fail early, so that the 
computer would normally run correctly for the rest of the day. 
Without this process, the MTBF would have been a few minutes. 

By the time SAGE was deployed (22 or 23 stations in the period 
1959-1963; sources disagree) it was nearly obsolete, since it 
was designed to detect bombers, not the new ICBMs. Nevertheless 
it was operational until 1979, when the ROCC (Regional 
Operations Control Centers) system took over, using much 
higher-speed computers. One SAGE station continued operating 
until 1983. This last unit was donated to the Boston Computing 
Museum, since relocated to Moffett Field in Mountain View, 
California. The museum also has a tube panel from the Whirlwind 
I. Whirlwind II consoles turned up in the TV series Battlestar 
Galactica.

In spite of its limited military value, the SAGE system served as 
an excellent prototype for an air-traffic control system. The 
FAA operated its own AN/FSQ-7 systems for many years after SAGE 
was shut down. IBM's experience with these systems had a great 
deal to do with its later success in computer systems, and its 
dominance of the market for large computers. The IBM 7090 was 
essentially a solid-state version of the AN/FSQ-7/8. (The 7090 
has its own rich history, including hosting the first-ever 
multiuser APL system.)

 First CRT-based real-time user interface,
 First use of light gun to pick an item on the screen,
 First wide-area modem communications (1300 bps),
 First hot standby system for maximum uptime,
 First ground control of interceptor aircraft,
 The first in line microfilm fast processed 35 mm projection displays, preceding printer/plotters. A screen capture could be displayed within 30 seconds,
 First two-pass assembler, permitting symbolic addresses.

Thanks to Edward Cherlin, Simputer Evangelist, for all this information.
The photo (from Mitre) shows the rear panel wiring of FSQ-7 arithmetic element frame.

 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>256 x 256</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/IBM_ANFSQ7_Part_s1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>IBM consoles</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links>
            <link>http://www.mitre.org/about/photo_archives/sage_photo.html</link>
            <link>http://www.radomes.org/museum/equip/fsq-7.html</link>
            <link>http://ed-thelen.org/comp-hist/TheCompMusRep/TCMR-V02.html#Reminiscences</link>
            <link>http://www.smecc.org/sage_a_n_fsq-7.htm</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>IBM</manufacturer>
        <media>Tape</media>
        <name>AN/FSQ-7</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals></peripherals>
        <ports>Tape, punched cards, modem</ports>
        <power>3 MW</power>
        <price>$238 million, printer around $200,000 to $250,000</price>
        <production>1963</production>
        <ram>Core 8892-word</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;SYSTEM DIAGRAM&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;An AN/FSQ-7 installed in a 4-story SAGE Direction Center building.&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/IBM_ANFSQ7_Diagram_s1.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>2000 square meters / 275 tons</size>
        <sound>Speaker (see the ''Read more'' page)</sound>
        <speed>75 KIPS (KiloInstructions Per Second)</speed>
        <text>None</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1958</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
