<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts>
            <advert>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;XEROX RANGE, AUGUST 1985&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Xerox_6085_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
            </advert>
        </adverts>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>Unknown</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Xerox Mesa</cpu>
        <description>
The Xerox 6085 was the successor of the revolutionary Xerox Star, first commercial computer to use a graphical user interface (GUI) with the familiar desktop, icons and a mouse. 

The 6085 series was offered in models for network, remote (linked by Ethernet) and stand alone operation. The main unit was founded upon Xerox's Mesa 8 MHz processor which had 256 auxiliary registers and executed 48-bit-wide instructions. It also used an 80186 as an auxiliary processor. 

The basic system came with 1.1 MB of memory, expandable up to 3.7 MB, a 10 to 80 MB hard disk drive, two serial ports and a 15-inch high-resolution monochrome display. An optional card allowed the 6085 to run MS-DOS software.

The operating system and GUI interface was called ViewPoint. It also came from the Star. It was written in a language developed at  Xerox PARC in the 1970's and also called Mesa. This strongly-typed and structured high-level language, would have a large influence on future well known languages like Pascal or C. 

Two improved versions were launched afterwards, the 6085-II with an almost twice as fast processor, and the XPIW (Xerox Publishing Illustrator's Workstation), basically a 6085 workstation with a scanner.
Sadly, like the Alto, the 6085 didn't meet a large success in spite of numerous vanguard concepts, mainly because the Xerox marketing policy was, at the time, above all directed towards copiers rather than computers.
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>880 x 697 dots</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Xerox_6085_System_s1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>95 key Typewriter style with 20 funtion keys and numeric keypad</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Xerox</manufacturer>
        <media>5.25 floppy drive, 10 to 80 MB HDD</media>
        <name>6085</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals>Unknown</peripherals>
        <ports>2 serial ports</ports>
        <power>Built-in power supply unit</power>
        <price>From $4995</price>
        <production>1989</production>
        <ram>1.1 MB up to 3.7 MB</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>Unknown</size>
        <sound>Yes, see below</sound>
        <speed>8 MHz</speed>
        <text>Bit-map characters</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram>Unknown</vram>
        <year>1985</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
