<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>Second Z80-A (I/O and display)</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80-A</cpu>
        <description>
The MBC-1200 and MBC-1250 are two 8-bit CP/M machines intended for business market. They were the first Sanyo business machines to have graphics capability.

They feature a high-resolution 640 X 400 dot matrix for graphic displays or a 40 line X 80 character text mode. The auxiliary CPU ensures high speed execution of graphics, while the detachable ergonomic keyboard and coiled cable enhance ease of use. 

There was no difference between the 1200 and 1250 models except that they left the factory with 1 or 2 drives installed. It was often done that a 1200 model would have a drive added by the dealer, as it was sometimes less expensive to add the Teac 5.25&amp;quot; disk drive than buy the 1250, or often the 1200s were more available in stock. 

The Sanyo MBC-1250 was the last CP/M-80 computer Sanyo sold to the US Business System market. Preceding it were the MBC-1000 series and the MBC-1100 series, all of which had integral monitors. When the not-so-IBM-compatible MBC-550 was introduced with a 3.58 MHz 8088 CPU, 128 KB of memory, and one 160 KB SSDD disk drive, this computer had TWO 4.0 MHz Z80A CPUs and 640 KB disk drives.

____________

Thanks to Victor Frank and Rusty Beard for most of the info !
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>640 x 400 pixels</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/sanyo_mbc-1200_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full stroke 83 with 17 function keys and numeric keypad</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Sanyo</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 640 KB 5.25'' floppy discs</media>
        <name>MBC-1200 / 1250</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Japan</origin>
        <peripherals>Unknown</peripherals>
        <ports>Parallel Centronics, Serial RS-232</ports>
        <power>Built-in power supply unit</power>
        <price>&amp;pound;2294 (1250) (U.K., 1983)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>64 KB</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>41 (W) x 33.7 (D) x 37 (H) cm</size>
        <sound>Beeper</sound>
        <speed>4 MHz</speed>
        <text>80 chars x 25/33/40 lines</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1982</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
