<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts>
            <advert>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT #1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Doctors, it gonna cure your work&amp;quot; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;ITT 3030, the absolute intelligence&amp;quot;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/itt_3030_pub-medecins_1_s.gif</link>
            </advert>
            <advert>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT #2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;The new revolutionnary modular system&amp;quot; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; So you say... &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;ITT 3030, the absolute intelligence&amp;quot; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Not less ! &amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/itt_3030_pub_1_s.gif</link>
            </advert>
        </adverts>
        <builtInGames>Basic Microsoft 5.0 delivered on disks</builtInGames>
        <colors>16</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80A (Intel 8086 optional)</cpu>
        <description>
The ITT 3030 is a modular system with several options available. The original CPU for example is a Z80A, but a 8086 CPU board was available...

More floppy disk drives and hard disks (5, 10 and 15 MB) can be added. The average access time of the hard-disks is 170ms, and the transfer rate 600 kb/s.

It is also possible to add up to two 8&amp;quot; disk drives in addition to the original 5''1/4 disk-drives. They can be simple-sides/simple-density (256k) and are thus compatible with the IBM 3740 format, or double-sided/double-density (1024kb).

Two monitors were proposed. A greenich monochrome one (80 x 24), and a color one being able to display 512 x 512 pixels and 16 colors. But these monitors could also be replaced with a TV.

The ITT 3030 works under CP/M, MP/M or BOS. It was delivered with CP/M and user documentations.

The following software were sold with the machine : CP/M, Microsoft Basic 5.0, Cobol, Fortran, Pascal (UCSB), Mailmerge and Supersport. Were also available : Calcstar, Wordstar, Datastar and many professional software (for doctors for example).

The ITT-3030 was in fact conceived by Standard Electric Lorenz, a subsidiary of ITT RFA.

About BOS operating system, Ian Turner (from U.K.) clarifies:

Bos was an independent company who created a truly 'portable' (between different types of computers) operating system and sofware. They specialised in accounting packages but the OS was quite excellent and the name was the acronym of &amp;quot;Business Operating Software&amp;quot;. They were highly successful until the early 1990's when they were bought by an insurance company and slowly migrated into an accounts software company running under Unix.
I was a major developer and reseller for them and was instrumental in the link between Bos and ITT, who offered Bos as a package with their systems. The company still exists.

More information from Thomas Bourke:
BOS was originally developed by CAP Ltd who were *the* consulting company for IT in the 1970's - 80's - the eventually were taken over by a French Company with the resulting name of Cap Gemni Sogeti.
Anyway, I digress, CAP didn't know what to do with BOS, so they effectively spun it of into a company called MPSL (Micro Process Software Ltd - if my memory serves).
It sold BOS and a bunch of horizontal packages (payroll, accounting, word processing, spreadsheet et al) both direct and through a series of dealers throughout the (english) speaking world.
Eventually MPSL (by now called BOS Software Ltd) was taken over by MISYS, a UK software/ services company. MISYS ran a VAN (value added network) for Insurance Brokers, hence the confusion with insurance companies - but they did and do other things as well - mainly for financial organisations (but hey, they're big, so they do lots of things!).
An MBO bought the remaining pieces in March 1999 and TIS Software Ltd now owns BOS...



 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>512 x 256, 512 x 512</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/itt_3030_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>QWERTY/AZERTY full-stroke keyboard, numeric keybad, editing keypad, 8 function keys, 128 non-ASCII characters, lower case and accuented letters, 32 semi-graphic characters, auto-repeat keys</keyboard>
        <language>Basic Microsoft 5.0 delivered on disks</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>ITT</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 5.25'' disk-drives (double side, double density), 280k eachaverage access time : 250msUp to 3 disk-drives mounted</media>
        <name>3030</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals>64k RAM expansions, 5''1/4 and 8'' disk-drives, hard-disks (5,10,15 Mb), 8086 CPU, color video board, NTSC TV interface, graphic board, 8087 arithmetic coprocessor, real-time clock, 4 x RS232c interfa</peripherals>
        <ports>RS 232c, Centronics, Video output</ports>
        <power>Built-in PSU (250-300w)</power>
        <price>Z80, 64k RAM, 2 x 5''1/4 (280k), RS232 interface, Basic = 4155  (France, 82)80186, 256k RAM, 2 x 5''1/4 (560k), 5Mb hard-disk = 7415  (France, 82)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>64kb (up to 256kb with 64k addons)</ram>
        <rom>2kb (up to 32kb)</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;COLOR PICTURE&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Bad picture, but the only one in color so far...&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/itt_3030_2.jpg</link>
            </shot>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;HARD-DISK&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;A hard-disk is mounted to the right side of the ITT-3030.&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/itt_3030_3.gif</link>
            </shot>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;WOMAN...&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;A courageous woman working on an ITT-3030 with a printer and a hard-disk plugged to the machine.&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/itt_3030_woman_1.gif</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>12,5kg</size>
        <sound>Beeper</sound>
        <speed>4Mhz (8086 : 6Mhz)</speed>
        <text>80 x 24 / 64 x 24</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>February 1982</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
