<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>16 colours from a 4096 color palette</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>Cirrus Logic CL-GD video subsystem, Math coprocessor</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Intel 80386DX</cpu>
        <description>
FM R 70 wasn't just an expensive IBM Compatible, but a very sophisticated machine at its time featuring some newly added features common to most modern computers today. In example: 
 It came stock with 584 KB Base Memory, and 2MB of Extended RAM Memory (in newly developed SIMMS).
 It featured a newly developed Cirrus Logic CL-GD video subsystem, adapted by many proprietary manufacturers of the late 1980's early 1990's.
 It featured an i386-DX processor, as well as an optional mathematics coprocessor.
 It ran at about 16Mhz and ran MS-DOS and any variations of PC Compatible software, as well as Miscrosoft Windows.
 It used the AT style Keyboard, 2 5&amp;quot; Floppy's, or one 3.25 Floppy and one 5&amp;quot; floppy, VGA/VESA technology and ISA bus.
 It also featured a Thomas Conrad ethernet adapter. 

Preceding i286 processor models was called FM-R60 (high-resolution model) and FM-R50 (standard 640x400 dot resolution model).

R60 and R50 had a sub-model with HDD (FM-R60HD /FM-R50HD) and without HDD(FM-R60FD/FM-R50HD).

Mainly, these machines were used as a terminal of Fujitsu M-series(M-3xx/7xx) mainframe, with a F6650 connection card (interface card) and a F6680 emulator software. 


 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>1120 x 750 dots</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/fujitsu_fmr70_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>JIS (Japanese Industrial Standard) keyboard (117 key)or &amp;quot;OYAYUBI-shift&amp;quot; Keyboard or Extended Emulator Keyboard (for terminal emulation)</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Fujitsu</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 5.25'' floppy drives or 1 x 3.5''+ 1 x 5.25''. 3.5'' 40 MB HDD (probably SCSI)</media>
        <name>FM R 70</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Japan</origin>
        <peripherals>Thomas Conrad ethernet adapter.</peripherals>
        <ports>3 expansion slots, 2 memory slot, Serial RS-232C, Parallel Centronics, FDD-I/F,  SCSI-I/F</ports>
        <power>Built-in PSU</power>
        <price>From $2998 to $3995 according to versions </price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>584 KB + 2 MB extended RAM up to 10 MB</ram>
        <rom>16KB</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>47 (W) x 38.5 (D) x 12.5 (H) cm / 18 kg</size>
        <sound>Built-in PC speaker</sound>
        <speed>16 MHz (succeeding model had an i386/25MHz)</speed>
        <text>80 columns x 25 lines (2byte-KANA 40x25) 24dot KANA/KANJI-character</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram>VRAM; Graphic VRAM 512KB + Text VRAM 16KB</vram>
        <year>1988</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
