<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>2 x 5.25'' disk drives</builtInGames>
        <colors>16</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Intel 8086 &amp;amp; Zilog Z80A</cpu>
        <description>
The model number was FM-16s, and it was sold in the USA from about 1983 to around 1985.

It had dual processors on daughter boards, one with a Zilog Z-80a and the other with an i8086 on a true 16-bit bus. Hard drives were external, connecting through a SCSI host adapter. The machine could have up to 2MB of RAM on a proprietary expansion card, and ran at 8MHz. It had a 640x480 16 color display and 104 keys keyboard.

CP/M-86, WordStar, SuperCalc and the C/PM-86 operating system were bundled with the basic purchase; but the FM-16 could also run CP/M 2.2, a proprietary version of MS-DOS 1.0, Concurrent CP/M-86 and PICK. If all were installed in partitions on the hard drive, you had a choice of OS at boot time.

Ron Edelstein adds:
Actually, the FM-16s had a video of 640x400 (not 480). It was a double-scanned format using 16 colours. Much better and sharper than the later IBM EGA standard, even though IBM used 480 lines. Using a proprietary version of MS-DOS, it could run any software not requiring graphics (i.e. text mode). The difference in video prevented it from displaying IBM graphics displays unless they were specifically recompiled for the FM-16s, as were SuperCalc and WordStar.




 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>640x400</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/fm16beta.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full-stroke keyboard</keyboard>
        <language></language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Fujitsu</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 5.25'' disk drives</media>
        <name>FM 16 Beta</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Japan</origin>
        <peripherals>Monochrome or colour monitor, 1 to 2 MB expansion RAM card (about $1,000/MB), SCSI 13 MB hard disk ($1300)</peripherals>
        <ports>Unknown</ports>
        <power>Built-in PSU</power>
        <price>About $3,300 with colour monitor, 128 KB RAM and two DS/DD 5.25'' floppy drives</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>up to 2 MB</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>Unknown</size>
        <sound>Unknown</sound>
        <speed>8 Mhz</speed>
        <text>Unknown</text>
        <type>Home Computer</type>
        <vram>Unknown</vram>
        <year>1983</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
