<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>2 x 5''1/4 disk-drives (360k each)</builtInGames>
        <colors>Yes (Color graphic board included, but built-in monitor is monochrom)</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Intel 8088</cpu>
        <description>
A (trans)portable PC-XT computer made by Zenith, with double 5''1/4 disk drives and amber monitor built-in (23cm). 

The computer is unusual in that the 2 built-in disk drives are mounted in a tilting case, on top of the computer. The keyboard folded up over the CRT (if you look at the picture just rotate the keyboard in place so that the spacebar is at the top of the machine). It forms the cover over the CRT.
the cable went into the pop top.

To the right of the two 5.25&amp;quot; floppys is a dark rectangular area. That is an open space for the keyboard and power cable.

The Z-160 was equiped with a color graphic board which could be used with external monitor.

_________

William Pociengel reports:

You could remove one of the floppys and add a hard drive (with an additional card?), you had to format the HD with debug. You could also change the occilator crystal for overclocking but then you had to retune the video circuitry to get the image back to full screen. Original speed was approx 4.78Mhz? same as a standard PC of the day but by changing the crystal you could get up to (on mine at least) a blazing ~5Mhz (whoopie! ;-). I _think_ there was a IC socket for an 8087 on the motherboard (if memory serves me correctly). I ran DR-dos and Desqview (no mouse at the time but it had a serial port, so later you could add one -when they became available-). This was one heavy machine as I recall running through JFK trying to catch a flight while hauling this puppy.
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>320 x 200 (CGA)</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/zenith_z160-pc.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>QWERTY full-stroke keyboard, 84 keys, 10 function keys.</keyboard>
        <language></language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Zenith Data Systems</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 5''1/4 disk-drives (360k each)</media>
        <name>Z-160 PC</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals>optional 20 MB hard disk</peripherals>
        <ports>2 serial ports, parallel port, 4 x IBM extension slots</ports>
        <power>Unknown</power>
        <price>$2799 (USA, 1984)128 KB model : 4565   (France, 1984)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>128 KB (upgradable to 640 KB)</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;Z-160 PC&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Another picture of this beast&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/zenith_z160-pc_2.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>approx. 24'' (W) x 10'' (H) x 28'' (D) / 33 lbs</size>
        <sound>Beeper</sound>
        <speed>4.78 MHz ?</speed>
        <text>80 x 25 / built-in amber screen (23cm)</text>
        <type>Transportable</type>
        <vram>Unknown</vram>
        <year>1984</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
