<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>2 x 600 KB 8'' double sided disk-drives (some systems were sold with single sided drives)</builtInGames>
        <colors>black and white</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu></cpu>
        <description>
This was not a really a computer but rather a wordprocessing system.

The full-text monitor could display 70 lines of 102 characters. The text could be black on a white background, or the inverse.

The Xerox 860 was equipped with one of the first WYSIWYG word processors: BravoX (later called &amp;quot;Xerox Document System Editor&amp;quot;) which was originally developed for the 1972 Xerox Alto and became the predecessor of virtually all modern word processors

Two 8&amp;quot; disks (600 kb) stored the files. Each disk catalog could store up to 560 files.

The system was sold with a Diablo printer, which was bidirectional and could print 40 characters per second. Up to three Xerox 860 could share one Diablo printer. The printer spooler could store up to 20 documents waiting to be printed.

The Xerox 860 could also be used to write and send electronic mails or work with data-bases through an Ethernet network.

There was another version called 'Supertext' which was the same system but with a smaller screen (24 x 102 characters).

These kind of systems were very expensive!
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>None</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/xerox_860_2.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>AZERTY/QWERTY full-stroke keyboard, 48 keys, 20 function keys</keyboard>
        <language></language>
        <links>
            <link>http://www.spies.com/aek/pdf/xerox/alto/BravoXMan.pdf</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Xerox</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 600 KB 8'' double sided disk-drives (some systems were sold with single sided drives)</media>
        <name>860</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals>Printer</peripherals>
        <ports></ports>
        <power>PSU built-in</power>
        <price>16115   (France, 82)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>128 kb</ram>
        <rom></rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size></size>
        <sound>None</sound>
        <speed></speed>
        <text>102 x 70 (A4 monitor)</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>March 1980</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
