<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>Unknow</builtInGames>
        <colors>greenish monochrome monitor</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Intel 8088</cpu>
        <description>
This Word Processor was originally produced by Syntrex Inc. Eatontown, New Jersey and sold under the brand of Olivetti. This was in 1980 (Version 1 of Syntrex Operating System was not sold); in 1981 the completely redesigned Version was sold with the system worldwide. 

The picture shows the base unit of the ETS 1010 (Electronic Typing System) It came with a display unit and one could attach an electronic typewriter (usually an ET121 or ET221) or a keyboard.

The cabinet socket plugged into a central storage device which could support 8 or 16 ETS units at a time plus 2 printers. There was a 10 MB hard drive option (later 20 MB Winchester HDD) which was the size of a chest freezer.

A variety of daisy wheel printers could be used with the system: PR430 / DY310 / DY450 / ET121 / ET221

There also existed an ETS2010 which was an updated version. It used an 80186 CPU, had more memory and was compabitable with all data on ETS1010.

________

Contributor: Robert Scrivener, Dr. Joachim Mueller, Charles Moss
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Unknow</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/olivetti_006A_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Unknow</keyboard>
        <language>Unknow</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Olivetti</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 5''1/4 disk-drives</media>
        <name>ETS 1010</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Italy</origin>
        <peripherals>10 or 20 MB hard disk, daisy wheel printer</peripherals>
        <ports>Communication port, Cabinet socket, Keyboard socket, Monitor socket, Power input</ports>
        <power>Built-in PSU</power>
        <price>Unknow</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>128 KB</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;REAR&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/olivetti_006A_2.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>15 x 13 x 7 inches</size>
        <sound>Unknown</sound>
        <speed>Unknow</speed>
        <text>Unknow</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>??? Unknow</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
