<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>2 x 5''1/4 disk-drives (350 KB each)</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome amber</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>Second Z-80A for CRT, real time clock, keyboard interface; 8741 and 8749 printer controllers, 8749 keyboard scanner</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80A - Optional Intel 8088</cpu>
        <description>
This transportable computer was originally produced by Access Matrix Corporation, San Jose, CA. The Company name then changed to Actrix Corporation. The machine was thus named Access, then Actrix.

It had a built-in printer (132 characters, 80 cps, using normal paper 20cm wide) and  an acoustic modem (300 and 1200 baud). The rubber cups (to put the phone handset in) are located behind the printer paper.

It also had a monochrome built-in monitor and two 5''1/4 disk-drives (360kb each).

The Actrix DS used a Z80A processor but was also equipped with an optional Intel 8088 card for IBM-PC compatibility.

It shipped with several software:
CP/M 2.2 operating Sytem
Microsoft M Basic (w/8088 co-processor
Digital Research C Basic
Communications
Perfect Writer, Perfect Speller, Perfect Filer, Perfect Calc
Access Font, and Access Language
Personal Perle
Money Maestro
Hard case or soft, padded case were optional.

The Actrix DS was presented at the Las-Vegas Comdex in November 1983. There was another model called the Actrix SS with a 170k 5''1/4 disk-drive. Actrix seems to mean &amp;quot;ACcess maTRIX&amp;quot;
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>64 graphic characters</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/actrix_ds_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full-stroke keyboard with numeric keypad and 15 function keys</keyboard>
        <language></language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Actrix</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 5''1/4 disk-drives (350 KB each)</media>
        <name>Actrix DS</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals>80 CPS bi-directional impact dot matrix: 40-80 characters per line; full graphics capability. Came with optional tractor feed.MODEMS: 300-baud acoustic coupler and Direct-Connect</peripherals>
        <ports>Two RS-232C with software selectable baud rate (61-9600)Parallel with Centronics compatible and bi-directional modesOne IEEE-488Composite video out jack8'' external disk drive interface (optional)</ports>
        <power>95 to 135 VAC or 190 to 270 VAC, 47 to 63 Hz (110 or 240 selectable).</power>
        <price>3090$ (USA, november 1983)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>64 KB or 256 KB with the 8088 processor</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>33 pounds</size>
        <sound>Unknown</sound>
        <speed></speed>
        <text>Full 96 ASCII upper and lower case, high resolution text characters. 7x9 character matrix in a 9x11 block with descenders</text>
        <type>Transportable</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1983</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
