<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>up to four 5.25'' or 8'' floppy disks, and optional  5 or 10 Mb Winchester hard-disks</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome monitor</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Zilog Z80A (4 MHz) or Z80B (6 MHz)</cpu>
        <description>
The BR1000Ms were Brazilian professional computers.
The BR1000M's hardware was the same as Cromemco's, and the so-called BR1000 operating system was in fact Cromix, a UNIX flavor designed to run on Cromemco's hardware.

Two models of the BR1000M were available: one with a Z80A processor at 4 MHz, capable of handling up to 4 dumb terminals, one of which was also used as the system console; and a &amp;quot;high end&amp;quot; model with a Z80B processor at 6 MHz, capable of handling up to 2 more terminals.

RAM size was one 64-KB system RAM board plus one additional 64-KB board for each terminal, all plugged into S100 slots. The first machines used 8-inch floppy drives, later upgraded to 5-1/4-inch units and, eventually, to 5- or 10-MB Winchester hard disks, keeping a floppy drive for data backup.

The picture shows a late-model (1985) terminal; that casing, designed by Brascom's industrial director (nickname Bubby), earned him a prominent design award. Unlike previous models, this one was capable of displaying graphic characters such as lines, corners and blocks.

In 1985, Brascom introduced a 6-MHz Z80B-based microcomputer running the CP/M operating system. This computer, called Foxy, was equipped with the above-mentioned late-model encasing and two external 5-1/4-inch floppy drives. This product never quite made it, due to Brascom's increasing financial problems and its final closedown in about 1986.

Thanks to Claudio Chagas for all this information.
Picture : Club Old Bits
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Yes, in last models</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/brascom_br1000.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full stroke QWERTY keyboard with numeric keypad, 69 keys</keyboard>
        <language></language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Brascom</manufacturer>
        <media>up to four 5.25'' or 8'' floppy disks, and optional  5 or 10 Mb Winchester hard-disks</media>
        <name>BR-1000M</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Brazil</origin>
        <peripherals>S100 cards</peripherals>
        <ports>S100 bus</ports>
        <power>Built-in CPU</power>
        <price></price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>64 KB + 64 KB for each dumb terminal (up to 6)</ram>
        <rom>6 Kb</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size></size>
        <sound>Beeper</sound>
        <speed>4-6 Mhz</speed>
        <text>25 lines x 80 char.</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1982</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
