<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>Basic</builtInGames>
        <colors>8</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80 clone</cpu>
        <description>
The MicroTim is a Romanian unlicenced ZX Spectrum clone. It is one of the first models made at the factory in Timisoara, western Romania in the early 1980s. MicroTim stands for &amp;quot;Micro&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;TIMisoara&amp;quot;. It was designed at Polytehnica University from Timisoara (former TUT - Technical University of Timisoara, former IPTVT - &amp;quot;Traian Vuia&amp;quot; Polytechnical Institute), but its large scale fabrication started and continued at the Fabrica de Memorii Timisoara (the Computer Memory Factory). 

When the ZX Spectrum appeared in the early 80's, three unlicenced Romanian clones were developped almost independently. These were developped in three main university centres from Timisoara, called initially microTim, and then TimS (from TIMisoara and Spectrum), Cluj-Napoca called Prae (which means &amp;quot;beginning&amp;quot; in latin) and Bucharest called aMIC (translated as &amp;quot;aSMALL&amp;quot;). These were developped using a combination of the &amp;quot;black box&amp;quot; principle and illegally obtained desings. The &amp;quot;Black Box &amp;quot; approach was widely developped and used in Eastern Block for developping electronic devices. The same principle was used in Eastern Germany to make the best PC in the east called &amp;quot;Robotron&amp;quot;. Unformally, &amp;quot;Black Box&amp;quot; means replacing a chip or a groups of chips that I do not know (or do not have) with another group that has same input and output signals.

The Cluj group dissapeared quite quickly, but Timisoara and Bucharest continued making spectrum based computers until early 1990s. Timisoara choose to further integrate and extend the model (as Sinclar did). The main designer behind TimS is eng. Dumitru Panescu who reached quite a mastery skill in integrating spectrum designs. His last prototype of TimS (it was never produced) integrated all spectrum firmware into one computer including a CP/M option. At start-up the user would select by pressing a key what does he or she wants to use. 

It has an original &amp;amp; small keyboard (40 keys) with statements and functions labeled next to the keys, like on the ZX Spectrum. The system is powered by an external power supply.
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>None, text mode only</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/timisoara_microtim_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Strange keyboard. 40 keys. Functions &amp;amp; statements labeled next to the keys</keyboard>
        <language>Basic</language>
        <links>
            <link>http://www.homecomputer.de/</link>
            <link>http://www.ionicol.com/</link>
            <link>http://www.thinkingdeep.com/site_en/history.html</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>IPTVT (Traian Vuia Polytechnical Institute)</manufacturer>
        <media></media>
        <name>MicroTim</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Romania</origin>
        <peripherals></peripherals>
        <ports>Power in, parallel port, serial port, cassette interface, RGB video output, RF TV output, expansion port</ports>
        <power>External power supply</power>
        <price>About 18,000 lei ($900)</price>
        <production>early 90</production>
        <ram>32, 64 or 128 KB</ram>
        <rom>16+4 KB BIOS, later improved to 32+4</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;MICROTIM&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Note that the keyboard of this model is slightly different from the one pictured on the main page (larger spacebar for example).&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/timisoara_microtim_2.jpg</link>
            </shot>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;BEIGE VERSION&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Microtim_System_1.jpg</link>
            </shot>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;BOTTOM LABEL&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Iptvt_Microtim_Label_1.jpg</link>
            </shot>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;REAR&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/timisoara_microtim_rear.jpg</link>
            </shot>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;INSIDE&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Iptvt_Microtim_Inside_1.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size></size>
        <sound>1 voice</sound>
        <speed>2 MHz, later improved to 3.5 MHz in the TimS</speed>
        <text>32 columns x 24 lines</text>
        <type>Home Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1986</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
