<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>MSX Basic V4.1, MSX View, Japanese text editor, a spread sheat and a sample program</builtInGames>
        <colors>16 / 16 - 256 / 16 among 512 / 19268</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>Video chip must be compatible with the Yamaha VG9938 or V9958, sound chip must be compatible with the General Instruments AY8910</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Zilog Z80A and R800 (16 Bit RISC)</cpu>
        <description>
This system is a MSX Turbo R. It is one of the last MSX computer ever made. It is the successor of the MSX 2+ systems and thus has many characteristics in common. New features include a new PCM sound chip which can sample sound up to 15 KHz and replay up to 22 kHz. There is an internal microphone for the PCM unit. There is also an additional CPU, the R800 wich is a 16-bit RISC processor. The user can select the CPU (Z80 or R800) by software.

The FS-A1 GT follows the FS-A1 ST, and so introduces some improvements over it. Due to some minor bugs discovered, the mainboard is a bit different (e.g. FM-PAC part is redesigned to decrease influence of the noise from computer's digital parts). The MSX-BASIC, version 4.1 instead of 4.0, has MIDI extensions. Indeed the FS-A1 GT has a MSX-MIDI interface built-in with MIDI in/out connectors! The RAM size is of 512 KB, instead of 256 KB. The MSX-DOS is now version V2.31. There is a SVHS video port and the size of the SRAM is now 32 KB.

MSX View, developed by ASCII &amp;amp; HAL, is a Windows-style graphic interface. It is built-in ROM. The OS is delivered with programs such as Page Edit, PageView, Page Link, VShell, VTed, VPaint and VDraw) on 512kB ROM DISK (C: drive). There is no tape recorder port, so strictly speaking, it's not an MSX! 

Panasonic stopped the production of the Turbo R when they launched the 3DO game system in 1992. They failed with this system and never returned to MSX.
Lot of extensions, however, were produced by third-party companies to enhance the Turbo R, among them, an OPL4 Sound Card, a VGA card with lot of hardware sprites and IDE or SCSI interfaces.

________

Source : The Ultimate MSX FAQ
David Heremans reports:
There is a mixed mode where you can have +4096 colors
simultaneously with an extra 16 indexed colors so that still pictures in
full color can be displayed while the index palatte of 16 redefinable colors
can be used for all kind of effects. But trying to display that would
probably be a litle long for the small space reserved for it on the
page.
 


</description>
        <emulators>
            <emulator>
                <description>Excellent free MSX emulator that can reproduce MSX, MSX2, MSX2+, and Turbo-R. The emulator also supports the SVI318/328, and ColecoVision systems !</description>
                <link>http://www.bluemsx.com/</link>
                <name>BlueMSX</name>
                <platform>Windows emulator</platform>
            </emulator>
            <emulator>
                <description>This new MSX emulator can reproduce, among many other MSX, MSX2and  MSX2+ machines, both Panasonic Turbo-R models. Be sure to get the catapult frontend and the system roms from FUNET. </description>
                <link>http://openmsx.sourceforge.net/</link>
                <name>openMSX - The MSX emulator that aims for perfection.</name>
                <platform>Multiplatform emulator</platform>
            </emulator>
        </emulators>
        <graphics>64 x 48 / 256 x 192 / 256 x 212 / 512 x 212 / 512 x 424</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/panasonic_turbor-a1-gt_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full-stroke keyboard, JIS standard layout, 91 keysbuilt-in software selector switch, reset button, disk removal button, auto-fire speed adjustment knob, Pause button</keyboard>
        <language>MSX Basic V4.1, MSX View, Japanese text editor, a spread sheat and a sample program</language>
        <links>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=775</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=290</link>
            <link>http://cobit.mma.com.br/materias/msxTurboRII.htm</link>
            <link>http://www.file-hunter.com/</link>
            <link>http://www.chez.com/msxfr/turbor.html</link>
            <link>http://www.faq.msxnet.org/msxtr.html</link>
            <link>http://www.chez.com/msxfr/msxviewp.html</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Panasonic</manufacturer>
        <media>Built-in 3.5'' disk drive (720 KB)</media>
        <name>FS A1 GT</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Japan</origin>
        <peripherals></peripherals>
        <ports>Joystick (2), Cartridge (2), RGB video output, Composite Video, SVHS output, Centronics, Microphone output, MIDI interface (IN &amp;amp; OUT), User port</ports>
        <power>100V&amp;plusmn;10% 50/60Hz, 22w</power>
        <price>99,800 yen (Japan, 1991)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>512 KB + 32 KB S-RAM (for backup)</ram>
        <rom>32 KB (BASIC/BIOS ROM)  + 32 KB (SUBROM MSX-BASIC V4.0) + 16 KB (MIDI-Basic ROM) + 16 KB (MSX Disk Basic) + 16 KB (Kanji Basic) + 512 KB (MSX View) + 2 MB (Japanese text editor, a spread sheat and a sample program) + MSX JE ROM (with approx. 32000 characters)</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;TURBOR FS A1 GT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/panasonic_fsa1gt_2.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>425 (W) x 292 (D) x 89 (H) mm / 3.4 Kg</size>
        <sound>AY-8910 + YM-2413 chip (9 channels of music) + PCM 8-bit synthesizer = 13 available channels!MSX-MIDI interface built-in</sound>
        <speed>Z80A: 3.579545 MHz / R800: 28.636360 MHz</speed>
        <text>80 x 25 / 40 x 25 / 32 x 25</text>
        <type>Home Computer</type>
        <vram>128 KB</vram>
        <year>1991</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
