<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>None</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Motorola MC-68000</cpu>
        <description>
The Sage IV was a no-compromise extended version of the Sage II.

There were 2 large PC boards in a SAGE IV.  The first had the CPU, 2 serial ports, PIO, GPIB, floppy controller, up to 512K DRAM.  This board was the same as the main board in the SAGE II.  The second board (which set above the first) had 4 more serial ports, hard disk controller, and another 512K DRAM.

The case was slightly taller as it contained the full height hard disk.

The built-in multi-user BIOS, written by Bill Bonham the Sage software guru, allowed the Sage to run several operating systems at once, serving up to 6 serial ports in real time within 1 MB of RAM... in 1983. At this time, PC/Intel based systems used a 8 bit-bus processor running twice slower, and a primitive operating system. So why this Sage system didn't become the standard of the future? 

In addition to the P-System delivered with the system, several companies in the world wrote various operating systems (CP/M, Posix, PDos, Tripos, Pluto...) and languages (Fortran, Lisp, Pascal...) for the Sage IV. 

Although Sage systems were the fastest personal systems of their days, and were intensively used by scientists and engineers for more than ten years, they are now totally forgotten, and so are all their powerful related OS's and software.
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>None</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Sage_IV_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Serial video terminal</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=607</link>
            <link>http://go.to/mwigan</link>
            <link>http://www.sageandstride.org/index.html</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Sage Computer Technology</manufacturer>
        <media>1 x 5.25'' 800 KB F.D. drives - 1 x 5 to 40 MB Winchester hard-disk</media>
        <name>Sage IV</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals></peripherals>
        <ports>6 x Serial - 1 x Parallel - 1 x GPIB</ports>
        <power>Buit-in power supply unit</power>
        <price>Unknown</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>1 MB</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>Unknown</size>
        <sound></sound>
        <speed>8 Mhz.</speed>
        <text>80 columns x 25 lines</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1983</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
