<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors></colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80-A</cpu>
        <description>
Comart was the computer system group that took over the Byte Shop/Computerland chain when it had financial difficulties in the late 70s. They were a large company distributing North Star systems, and similar equipments. The Communicator was their first effort in distributing a British-made system.

The Communicator is a S-100 bus system based around a main chassis with a 10-slot-mother-board. The system had 64 KB of RAM and came with three variations of dual floppy disk drives.

Several S-100 boards were available. They offered Viewdata/Prestel capabilities, or 18.7 MB hard disk, with 13.4 MB cartridge backup.

The system ran CP/M operating system. A smaller system called the Educator, with networking facilities, was also available.

Chris Coggins  adds:
The Communicator was upgraded over several years until the Communicator was given multi-user capability by running MP/M80 but finished off running Intel 386 processors with 512 KB RAM running CCP/M86.  Hard disk had grown to 40MB Rodime drive.
David Broad sold Comart to Kode International and 2 years later it lefts it's Cambridgeshire factory and moved to Swindon.  The Company went downhill, dropped the S-100 bus to use standard PC architecture but eventually closed.

 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics></graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Comart_Communicator_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Serial video terminal</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Comart</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 5.25'' floppy disc drives - 190 KB, 390 KB or 790 KB each</media>
        <name>Communicator</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>United Kingdom</origin>
        <peripherals>S-100 boards</peripherals>
        <ports>2 x Serial RS-232</ports>
        <power>Built-in power supply unit</power>
        <price>$3500</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>64 KB</ram>
        <rom></rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size></size>
        <sound></sound>
        <speed>Unknown</speed>
        <text>Depends on the video terminal used</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1979</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
