<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>No language but a software package</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Intel 80186</cpu>
        <description>
Like the HP-110 or the Sharp PC-5000, the Dulmont Magnum belongs to the first family of notebook computers with LCD screen (not yet back-lighted). Moreover, it was the first computer conceived and manufactured in Australia. It was also called Kookaburra (an Australian bird) for some export markets.

The Magnum was a PC-compatible system featuring an Intel 80186 processor, 96 KB of RAM, an 8 line LCD screen and several management software in ROM: word processor, spreadsheet, telecommunication, file manager, and appointment. Additional ROM software could be added thanks to two 128 KB cartridge slots.
A rechargeable Ni-Cad battery pack allowed ten to twelve hours of continuous use, and a lithium battery kept the content of the RAM memory when the system was turned off.
Due to various RAM/ROM configurations in the system, the drive letters assignation was specific to the Dulmont: drive A corresponded to the software in ROM, drives B and C, to each optional ROM expansion, D to the internal C-MOS RAM, E and F to the external floppy disc drives.
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Unknown</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Dulmont_Magnum_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full-stroke 76 keys with function and arrows keys</keyboard>
        <language>No language but a software package</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Dulmont</manufacturer>
        <media>C-MOS battery-backup RAM</media>
        <name>Magnum</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Australia</origin>
        <peripherals>2 x 5.25'' 360 KB F.D. unit</peripherals>
        <ports>2 x ROM cartridges, 2 x Serial, Parallel, Composite video, Expansion port</ports>
        <power>External power supply unit, Ni-Cad battery</power>
        <price>Unknown</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>96 KB up to 384 KB</ram>
        <rom>128 KB up to 384 KB</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>32(W) x 27,5(D) x 5,5(H) cm.  / 4.8 Kg</size>
        <sound>Internal speaker</sound>
        <speed>Unknown</speed>
        <text>40-80 characters x 8 lines</text>
        <type>Portable</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1984</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
