<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome or 256 colours (HRG option)</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>None</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80-A</cpu>
        <description>
Research Machines is based in Oxford, England and the RM-380Z was their first model. It was designed specifically for the education market and the vast majority of its users were in this area.

The computer was based around the Z80A processor. It had a clever physical bus made of ribbon cable with IDC crimp on connectors obviating the problems of poor connections associated with edge connectors.

The basic system was composed of a 4 KB main unit, a typewriter style separate keyboard and a monochrome monitor. Single or dual floppy disc drives could be inserted in the main housings. 8&amp;quot; floppy drives (2 x 500 KB) were also available as well as a High resolution colour graphics board.
The CP/M operating system was used to run lots of educational software.

Before and during the time that the BBC computers were introduced in English schools, the 380Z and its successor the Link 480Z met a great success, mostly due to their high reliability.

The RM-280Z should be the kit version of the 380Z but RM never shipped any kits but only pre-built 380Z machine, thinking better of the support problems it would cause.
_______________________</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>80 x 72 monochrome as standard320 x 192 16 colours  and 640 x 480 4 colours with optional HRG board</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/ResearchMachines_RM380Z_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full stroke 60 keys QWERTY layout</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links>
            <link>http://tech.groups.yahoo.com/group/380z/</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Research Machines</manufacturer>
        <media>Single or dual 5.25</media>
        <name>RM-380Z</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>United Kingdom</origin>
        <peripherals>Graphic and colour board, 8'' 500 KB floppy drives</peripherals>
        <ports>UHF TV, Composite video, Tape recorder, Parallel printer</ports>
        <power>Built-in power supply unit</power>
        <price>From &amp;pound;519</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>4 KB expandable to 56 KB</ram>
        <rom>2 or 3  KB (Monitor)</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>59.5 (W) x 42.5 (D) x 21.5 (H) cm</size>
        <sound>None</sound>
        <speed>4 MHz.</speed>
        <text>40 chars (later optional 80) x 24 lines</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1977</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
