<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>HD64B180 CMOS enhanced version of the Z80</cpu>
        <description>
The Husky Hawk has inherited the very solid case of the  Hunter. The screen was well protected with a thick layer of plastic and all the ports had protective coverings. However, it was not designed to take the rough treatment that the Husky could endure. For example, it could not being used in the rain.

The chicklet keyboard featured a numeric and arrow key keypad. However, Husky could produce 'cut down' versions dedicated to particular applications.

Several peripheral could be connected to the Hawk.
The Sidebox was designed to be used on the move and was powered by Hawk's internal batteries. It was firmly locked to the Bus expansion and accepted a portable 1200 baud modem, an analogue to digital converter, RAM and ROM disk expansions and a Parallel interface.
The 'Homebase' expansion required a mains supply and automatically connected the Hawk to a 2400 baud modem and charger whenever it was placed on it. 
A 3.5&amp;quot; disc drive unit called Oracle (made in Japan by Brother) and a bar-code reader also could be connected to the mini-DIN serial port.

The DEMOS operating system (for Disk EMulation Operating System) was a very compatible extended version of CP/M 2.2. All standard CP/M software - WordStar, CalcStar, Mbasic... - ran without problems. To overcome standard CP/M 80 column screen output, Husky used a  40 X 8 virtual window on a full size 80 x 25 screen. 

For custom application writers, Husky also provided a special version of Locomotive BASIC, a superset of Microsoft BASIC, also well known of Amstrad users. This version took advantage of the special facilities of the Hawk: graphics handling, both serial and infra-red ports, bar-code reader and file management using physical or virtual RAM and ROM disks.

 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>240 x 64 dots</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Husky_Hawk_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>68 key with numeric/arrows keypad</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Husky Computers Limited</manufacturer>
        <media>Battery backet RAM disk</media>
        <name>Hawk</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>United Kingdom</origin>
        <peripherals>Modem, A/D converter, RAM/ROM extensions, bar-code reader, floppy disc unit</peripherals>
        <ports>2xSerial ports (1xDB25, 1xMini-DIN), 37 pin bus extension, Infra-red transmitter</ports>
        <power>Nickel-cadmium battery - 35 hours autonomy</power>
        <price>&amp;pound;895</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>352 KB Battery backed</ram>
        <rom>96 KB + 32 KB space for user applications</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>21.6 (W) x 15.25 (D) x 2 (H) cm / 0.8 Kg</size>
        <sound>Beeper (4 octaves)</sound>
        <speed>6.144 MHz</speed>
        <text>40 chars. x 8 lines backlight LCD screen</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1987</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
