<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Z80A</cpu>
        <description>
After having launched a home computer, the Einstein, Tatung tried to tackle the small business market with this PC-2000 system. Ease of use, attractive price and expandability were their main desing criteria.

The PC-2000 was actually a standard CP/M based machine. However, a large range of powerful options could be added whitch impressively increased system capabilities:
 The serial interface board contained 14 RS232 serial ports and the PC-2000 could add up to 2 complete boards.
 The TTL I/O board had 64 Input/Output lines and again the PC-2000 could take 2 complete boards.
 The virtual disk board had a capacity of 256 KB and the PC-2000 could take up to 8 of them. 
 On the hard-disk card, up to 4 set of 5.25&amp;quot; or 8&amp;quot; drives were possible.
 Furthermore, Internal connectors allowed a colour graphic board and a dual 8&amp;quot; floppy disc controller to be connected.

Despite these unusual abilities and a good manufacturing quality, the PC-2000 was a real flop and very few of them were sold.
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Text only in basic version</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Tatung_PC5000_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full stroke 85 keys with 6 function keys and numeric keypad</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Tatung</manufacturer>
        <media>2 x 1 MB 5.25'' floppy disc drives</media>
        <name>PC-2000</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Ta&amp;iuml;wan</origin>
        <peripherals>Graphics display and board, Serial board, I/O board, FD/HD controllers</peripherals>
        <ports>Parallel Centronics, Serial RS232</ports>
        <power>Built-in power supply unit</power>
        <price>&amp;pound;1950 (U.K., 1984, monochrome version)</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>64 KB</ram>
        <rom>2 KB</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>45 (W) x 42.8 (D) x 62 (H) (CPU + monitor)</size>
        <sound>Beeper</sound>
        <speed>4 MHz</speed>
        <text>80 chars x 25 lines (9 x 12 resolution)</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram>4 KB</vram>
        <year>1984</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
