<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>Sinclair Basic</builtInGames>
        <colors>8 with two tones each (normal and bright)</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Zilog Z80 A</cpu>
        <description>
The goal with the TK95 was to offer a true Spectrum compatible system with a case and keyboard as strong and convenient as a Commodore 64.

The inside of the machine was neverthless quite similar to its predecessor, the TK-90, with some ROM improvements that increased the degree of compatibility and corrected some bugs (ROM No Maskable Interrupt) of the original Sinclair and Timex models.
 
Two BASIC command were added, TRACE and UDG (User Defined Graphics) that allowed the specific Brazilian characters to be printed. As the machine was only dedicated to Brazilian market, all the error messages were in Portuguese language. 

The TK-95 was one of the last machine made by Electronica. It didn't sell well because of the massive appearence and great success of MSX computers in South America.

Thanks to Dimitri Kokken for the picture

More information from Mario Villar (Uruguay):
Not all peripherals marketed for the ZX Spectrum were compatible with this machine, specially the Joystick Interfaces.
Microdigital also made peripherals for the TK line under it's own brand: An optical pen, RS-232 Interface, and modems.
In my country (Uruguay), this machine had great success, leaving it to implement a system information service over modem (like a BBS) specially dedicated to that machines, with a modem and interface built here. Also, there was a High Speed tape drive called &amp;quot;Hilow&amp;quot;, developed in Uruguay. It has a Snapshot button (NMI interrupt?) and two speeds. The few units ever made were incredibly reliable, still working today.

 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>256 x 192 dots</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Microdigital_TK95_System_2.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full stroke 57 keys</keyboard>
        <language>Sinclair Basic</language>
        <links>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=463</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=964</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=953</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=459</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=776</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=945</link>
            <link>http://www.tk90x.com.br</link>
            <link>http://www.kompaktservis.cz</link>
            <link>http://www.homecomputer.de/pages/f_sinclair.html</link>
            <link>http://www.algonet.se/~rsm/zx/zxclones.html</link>
            <link>http://tarjan.uw.hu/zxclones_en.htm</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Microdigital</manufacturer>
        <media></media>
        <name>Tk-95</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Brazil</origin>
        <peripherals>all of the Sinclair and third sources peripherals</peripherals>
        <ports>Expansion port, tape-recorder (1200 bauds), RF video out, Joystick, Bus expansion</ports>
        <power>External 9V DC power supply unit</power>
        <price>Unknown</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>48 KB</ram>
        <rom>16 KB (Basic &amp;amp; OS)</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;LARGER VIEW&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Microdigital_TK95_System_1.jpg</link>
            </shot>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;MANUAL COVER&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Microdigital_TK95_ManualCover_1.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>Unknown</size>
        <sound>1 voice / 10 octaves (via TV set)</sound>
        <speed>3.58 MHz</speed>
        <text>32 chars. x 24 lines</text>
        <type>Home Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>April 1986</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
