<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>RPN (Reverse Polish Notation) based</builtInGames>
        <colors></colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Serial 16-bit</cpu>
        <description>
The HP-9810 was the successor of the HP-9100. Although it kept software compatibility, its internal hardware organisation was completely different. The core memory was replaced with volatile MOS RAM chips and the display used the new technology of 7-segment light emitting diodes (LED) instead of cathode-ray tube.

Arithmetic routines were stored in ROM and user programs in RAM. Several RAM extensions, specialized ROM modules and peripherals (paper tape reader/puncher, line printer,  measuring instruments) could be connected to the basic model.

The standard version of this calculator included a magnetic card reader  located directly behind the two yellow keys at the top-right in the keyboard. While a thermal printer was available as an option, it could only print numeric characters unless you had the Alphanumeric Printer ROM.

The add-on ROMs for this machine came in the form of a block that plugged into the left side of the keyboard; each had its own specialized keys. You can see the edges of the ROM block in the picture; the 3x5 array of keys at the leftmost area of the keyboard is its top. It was common to have more than one ROM extension available in a single block, since you could only plug in one at a time.

With this first generation of programmable calculators, engineers eventually became independant from main frames and computer centers. They could write programs, save, recall and print them off-line; and even easily carry the computer from a place to another... it was a true revolution at the time.
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>None</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/HP_9810_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>75 keys in 3 parts</keyboard>
        <language>RPN (Reverse Polish Notation) based</language>
        <links>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=879</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=930</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=1068</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=950</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=141</link>
            <link>http://www.hpmuseum.org/hp9810.htm</link>
            <link>http://www.hpmuseum.net</link>
            <link>http://www.classiccmp.org/hp/9800.htm</link>
            <link>http://www.oldcalculatormuseum.com/hp9810a.html</link>
            <link>http://www.rheinfeld.de/andreas/9810.htm</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Hewlett Packard</manufacturer>
        <media></media>
        <name>HP-9810</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals>RAM and ROM modules, Peripherals I/O connector</peripherals>
        <ports>Unknown</ports>
        <power>Built-in power supply unit</power>
        <price>$2475</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>51 registers and 500 program steps</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots>
            <shot>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;KEYBOARD&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/HP_9810_System_2.jpg</link>
            </shot>
        </screenshots>
        <size>49,5 (W) x 40,6 (D) x 17,8 (H) cm / 15.4 Kg</size>
        <sound></sound>
        <speed>Unknown</speed>
        <text>3 lines of 15 numeric chars. Each line displays one register</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1971</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
