<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts>
            <advert>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;U.S. AD. (1983) #1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;First advert - January 1983&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Oki_IF800_Advert_1.jpg</link>
            </advert>
            <advert>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;U.S. AD. (1983) #2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;advert said:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Our all-in-one BMC IF-800 computer is easier for dealers to sell, customers to buy and OEM to use in their systems...&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ... You can upgrade to a 16 bit CPU which offers IBM PC compatible MS-DOS and CP/M-86...&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Oki_IF800_Advert_2.jpg</link>
            </advert>
            <advert>
                <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (JULY 1982)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;A rainbow in your office&amp;quot;&amp;lt;</description>
                <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/oki_if800_ad-rainbow.jpg</link>
            </advert>
        </adverts>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>8. Also available in monochrome version (8 shades)</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>Zilog Z80 A</cpu>
        <description>
This computer had an integrated dot printer which can print on 40 to 132 columns at 120 cps, a 12&amp;quot; color graphic monitor and a dual 5&amp;quot; disc drives. A lot of cards were designed to be placed into the three expansion slots: an 8&amp;quot; disk controler, centronics interface, IEEE488 port, ADC/DAC card or ram expansion (64 or 128 KB).

A bit of trivia: the video card has its own Z80 CPU.

Apparently this computer was marketed by BMC outside Japan.

Alexander Velin says :
There is OKI if 800 model 50, which is based on 8086, has 256 KB ram, spare keyboard, one 8&amp;quot; 560 KB floppy, 7 MB HDD. Mine has a MS DOS 1.15 on it...

More technical information from Bruce Grant:
I serviced IF-800's in the early 1980's.
The printer was a 7 pin matrix mechanically related to the Oki Microline 82 but largely software driven. It was a frightful device.
Both colour and monochrome screens were offered, and were excellent. The colour monitor had, as I recall, three seperate banks of 16K of RAM, one for each of the primary colours, providing an early form of 24-bit colour. Power for the main unit was provided through the monitor. Two people were needed to safely carry the colour monitor.
The floppy disks were made by YE-Data and offered good capacity for the time - in the order of 500KB. They were of the solenoid head loading type and were ponderously slow but generally quite reliable.
CP/M 2.2 and a standalone version of MS-Basic were supplied. Each system used its own disk format. Sadly, these were not interchangeable. Bitmapped graphics were implemented through the MS-Basic system only, as were the bezel-mounted screen &amp;quot;hotkeys&amp;quot;.
The IF-800 was crippled commercially by appearing on the market at the same time as the IBM PC-XT, which cost slightly less as I recall.
They were distributed in Canada by Canada Computer of Markham, Ontario.


 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>640 x 400 / 640 x 200</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/oki_if800_2.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full-stroke keyboard with separated numeric keypad</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>OKI</manufacturer>
        <media>Two 360 KB - 5.25'' FDD. Optional 16 MB H.D. and 6.3 MB removable cartridge</media>
        <name>IF 800</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>Japan</origin>
        <peripherals></peripherals>
        <ports>RS232c, light pen, ROM cartridge (20 KB), Tape, 4 x I/O Slots, 3 x accessory slots</ports>
        <power>Built-in PSU</power>
        <price>$4995</price>
        <production></production>
        <ram>64 KB / 128 KB / 256 KB</ram>
        <rom>Unknown</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>Unknown</size>
        <sound>1 voice - 5 octaves</sound>
        <speed>5 mHz</speed>
        <text>20 x 25 / 24 x 80</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram>192 KB (3 blocks of 64 KB)</vram>
        <year>1982</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
