<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors>Monochrome green</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>Optional 8087 math co-processor</coprocessor>
        <cpu>Intel 8088</cpu>
        <description>
The MAX-20 (for Matra AX-20) was the same machine as the Axel 20. The main difference between them was the removal of the function keys in front of the monitor. The 'E' version probably meant 'Education'

Although the machine was well conceived and the case offered a nice design, it had no success in the private sector because of its poor compatibility with the IBM-PC standard. However, about 1000 systems were sold to the French Department of Education as network servers (first networks established in schools, called 'Nano R&amp;eacute;seau').

Furthermore, as the computer was built by Comterm-Matra, a Franco-Canadian subsidiary of Matra, the Canadian Department of Education obliged schools to order the MAX-20 instead of the Apple Macintosh. Thee first deliveries occurred in early 1985. One year later, after having delivered 9000 computers, Comterm-Matra met with financial difficulties and ceased production. Thus, the machines quickly became obsolete and unusable in schools.
 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics>Unknown</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Matra_Max20_System_1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Full stroke 92 keys with numeric keypad and arrow keys</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Matra</manufacturer>
        <media>5.25'' disk-drive - 320 kb</media>
        <name>MAX 20</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>France</origin>
        <peripherals>Printers, disk-drives, V24 communication card, high resolution card, modem</peripherals>
        <ports>Parallel, optional Serial and Network</ports>
        <power>Built-in PSU - 65W</power>
        <price>Unknown</price>
        <production>1986</production>
        <ram>64 kb (up to 1 Mb)</ram>
        <rom>2 kb</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>42 (W) x 51 (D) x 38 (H) cm</size>
        <sound>Built-in speaker</sound>
        <speed>4,77 Mhz</speed>
        <text>80 chars x 24 lines</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1984</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
