<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>BBC BASIC. BCPL provided with package.</builtInGames>
        <colors>16 (8 colors + flashing option), True colour from the video data on LV-ROM</colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor>MOS 65C102 at 4MHz, Turbo co-processor model</coprocessor>
        <cpu>65C02</cpu>
        <description>
In 1986, the 900th Anniversary of the Norman Domesday Book, the BBC and 
the National Curriculum, amongst other UK bodies, endeavoured to 
produced a 20th Century equivalent. Recently the Domesday project has 
had renewed interest, as the sense of producing such an ambitious 
undertaking then storing the results on a strange, and now forgotten, 
format has been called into question many times since!

For old-computers.com readers, the interesting bits are not terribly 
interesting - but they are scarce. The presentation was viewable on one 
of two platforms - the main, and the one most associated with it, was 
the BBC Master AIV (Advanced Interactive Video). This isn't an 
'official' term - as far as Acorn and the BBC were concerned, they 
wanted schools to purchase the system in the belief that it was 
essentially what they were used to. The BBC Master was an off the shelf 
Master Turbo, with an additional SCSI interface (possibly 
electronically derived from the SCSI interface built into the ACW), and 
an additional filing system to access the LV-ROM.

The VP415 LV-ROM was an industrial Philips Laservision player, already 
'programmable' according to the Laservision standards. The storage was 
broken down into volumes, with data encoded along with the video 
content (which can be played separately). The SCSI interface allowed 
data retrieval but this was also possible via the RS-232 interface - 
and a module to allow the other machine popular in schools at the time 
access - the RM Nimbus. The actual data format on the disc was 
controlled by LV-DOS in the player, and VFS in the BBC series computer. 
Whilst the Master AIV was most definitely marketed for this 
application, the documentation is quite vague about whether a BBC B 
could be used, implying that merely the VFS ROM is required!

Video from the laserdisc was mixed using a genlock incorporated in the 
base of the VP415 with data generated by the Domesday applications and 
displayed on a SCART monitor.

Applications allowed searching of film content, further exploration of 
the information, such as going into a house pictured (within 
limitations, of course!), and statistical analysis of data gathered in 
a project that involved schools all over the UK. It's quite likely that 
many people of my generation contributed, in some small part, to the 
Domesday project.

Additional discs were produced for educational purposes, hoping to 
expand the applications of the AIV system, but the late 80s was to see 
the advent of Microsoft's &amp;quot;Multimedia PC&amp;quot; standard, Philips' own CDi, 
and many other CD (rather than LD) based systems. LV-ROM, in addition 
to the video and still frames, could store just under 400Mb of data on 
a 12&amp;quot; optical disc - whilst the video would take up more space on CD, 
the media was physically fragile and was eventually to be rendered 
obsolete with the end of the VP415.

Projects to restore the Domesday project are hampered by copyright law 
and the restrictions of accessing the data, The most successful is 
Leeds University's CAMeLION project, an emulated system, with some 
PC-based applications. I am undertaking my own 'accessible' project, to 
attempt to make the material useable in a wide range of consumer 
friendly appliances, but like everyone else, am tied by the fragility 
of the hardware (if anyone has parts for the VP415 I need spares!) and 
of course, copyright law.

___________

Thanks A LOT to Richard Kilpatrick for all this info.

 


</description>
        <emulators>
            <emulator>
                <description>This excellent site has a complete list of Acorn systems emulators</description>
                <link>http://www.nvg.org/bbc/emulators.php3</link>
                <name>The BBC Lives !</name>
                <platform>MS DOS emulator</platform>
            </emulator>
        </emulators>
        <graphics>640 x 256 (2 colors) / 320 x 256 (4 colors) / 160 x 256 (16 colors)</graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/acorn_BBC-Master-AIV_1s.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Standard QWERTY, 10 function keys + arrows, plus numeric keypad</keyboard>
        <language>BBC BASIC. BCPL provided with package.</language>
        <links>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=80</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=850</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=729</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=29</link>
            <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=121</link>
            <link>http://www.acornusers.org/</link>
            <link>http://acorn.chriswhy.co.uk/Computers/Domesday.html</link>
            <link>http://www.landfield.com/faqs/acorn/games/</link>
            <link>http://www.dmc12.demon.co.uk/retrotech/abc.htm</link>
            <link>http://www.strafom.force9.co.uk/bbc/Retrobbc/Index.htm</link>
            <link>http://8bs.com/</link>
            <link>http://bbc.nvg.org/</link>
            <link>http://www.stairwaytohell.com/</link>
            <link>http://www.poppyfields.net/acorn/</link>
            <link>news:comp.binaries.acorn</link>
            <link>news:comp.sources.acorn</link>
            <link>news:comp.sys.acorn.advocacy</link>
            <link>news:comp.sys.acorn.announce</link>
            <link>news:comp.sys.acorn.apps</link>
            <link>news:comp.sys.acorn.hardware</link>
            <link>news:comp.sys.acorn.misc</link>
            <link>news:comp.sys.acorn.networking</link>
            <link>news:comp.sys.acorn.programmer</link>
        </links>
        <manufacturer>Acorn Computer</manufacturer>
        <media>None</media>
        <name>BBC Master AIV</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>United Kingdom</origin>
        <peripherals>Philips VP415 LV-ROM, Acorn AKF-11 monitor (SCART), Acorn Trackerball (Marconi RB2).</peripherals>
        <ports>1MHz BUS, Analogue, RGB, Disk, RS423, User port, Econet, Tape, Parallel printer. Captive SCSI lead.</ports>
        <power>Built-in PSU, 240V AC</power>
        <price>&amp;pound;4,000+ (UK, 1986)</price>
        <production>1986-7? Very small run.</production>
        <ram>128 KB</ram>
        <rom>48K-128K, expandable, includes LVFS (Laservision Filing</rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>Complete set - heavy ;)</size>
        <sound>3 channels + noise &amp;amp; envelope control, 7 octaves</sound>
        <speed>Unknown</speed>
        <text>80 x 32/25 (2 colors) / 40 x 32/25 (2 or 4 colors) / 20 x 32 (16 colors) / 40 x 25 (Teletext display)</text>
        <type>Home Computer</type>
        <vram>Taken from main RAM, up to 44K?</vram>
        <year>1986</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
