<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computers>
    <computer>
        <adverts/>
        <builtInGames>None</builtInGames>
        <colors></colors>
        <controllers></controllers>
        <coprocessor></coprocessor>
        <cpu>32 to 2048 DEC Alpha RISC processors</cpu>
        <description>
With the T3D, Cray research introduced a new generation of Massively Parallel Processor (MMP) super computers.

The T3D integrated from 32 to 2048 processing elements (PE's). Each PE was composed of a DEC 21064 RISC chip, also known as DEC Alpha, with its own memory area, memory controller, and prefetch queue.

The DEC Alpha contained a floating point unit, an integer unit, both with 32 64-bit registers, a 128-bit bidirectional bus, and both instruction and data caches.

The PE's were combined in nodes of 2 PE's running at 150 MHz, along with two to 64 megabytes of memory and a network switch. The nodes were connected in a 3-D torus network configuration.

Memory was physically distribued among the processors, but was globally addressable (any processor could address any memory location in the system.

The global peak performance of a T3D was from 19 (128 PE's) to 307 (2048 PE's) GigaFlops (billions floating-point operations per second).

The system ran UNICOS MAX, the Cray Research's operating system. Each processor ran a minimal microkernel to handle frequently used functions, interprocessor communication and memory management. Major programming language were C and Fortran compilers

The T3D was tightly coupled to a CRAY C90 or CRAY Y-MP host system through a high speed channel, making host's resources (I/O functionality, I/O subsystem, high-speed disks) directly available to the T3D.

The Cray T3D was replaced by the T3E, the first supercomputer to sustain one teraflop (1 trillion F.P. calculations per second).


 


</description>
        <emulators/>
        <graphics></graphics>
        <hardwares/>
        <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Cray_T3D_System_s1.jpg</image>
        <keyboard>Video terminal</keyboard>
        <language>None</language>
        <links/>
        <manufacturer>Cray Research</manufacturer>
        <media></media>
        <name>T3D</name>
        <numGames></numGames>
        <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
        <peripherals></peripherals>
        <ports>2 to 32 I/O gateways - Peak I/O bandwidth: 12.8 Gbytes/s</ports>
        <power>PSU and cabinet cooled by computer coolant fluid (3M Fluorinert)</power>
        <price>Unknown</price>
        <production>1999</production>
        <ram>2 to 128 GB</ram>
        <rom></rom>
        <screenshots/>
        <size>1.9 m&amp;sup2; per cabinet (1 to 4 cabinets)</size>
        <sound></sound>
        <speed>150 MHz (processors) 19.2 to 307.2 GFLOPS (global system)</speed>
        <text>Depending on the video terminal</text>
        <type>Professional Computer</type>
        <vram></vram>
        <year>1993</year>
    </computer>
</computers>
