<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computer>
    <adverts>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;UK ADVERT, OCT. 1983&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Semitech_PiedPiper_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (JULY 1985)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Page 1&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/amstrad_cpc664_pub_haute-performabce-p1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT #3&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;With a cool teacher, computers is a child game&amp;quot; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Alice, the Basic teacher&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Matra_Alice_Adv_3.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;NEWBURRY BROCHURE #2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;According to this brochure, Newbury had four models:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Model M: Main Only&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Model MB: Main and with Batteries and display&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Model MD: Mains only with display&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Model MBS: Main and with Batteries and display with special low power consumption.  &amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Courtesy of &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;www.oldcomputers.freeserve.co.uk&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Grundy_Newbrain_Leaflet_Newburry_Inside.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;6000 MODEL&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Advert says:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt; WE HAVE A NEW APPROACH TO DISTRIBUTED PROCESSING THAT WORKS &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Already implemented are electronic mail, word processing, complete cost accounting with inventory control and more. The secret is a new technology called Functionally Structured Distribution (FSD). At last, a system to organize and manage distributed processing applications that is really up and running. FSD technology is especially applicable to installa&amp;shy;tions that require:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;bull; Unlimited expandability supporting extremely large data bases and terminals in many cities.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;bull; User-friendly software easily programmed in high level languages (COBOL, FORTRAN, and BASIC)&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;bull; System reliability (due to distributed hardware) while maintaining multiple levels of data security.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;bull; Compatibility with existing mainframes and networks (including the Bell System). &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; We are presently installing Billings 6000 Computer Systems which take full advantage of distributed processing utilizing FSD technology. The 6000 Computer supports multiple hard disk drives with capacities of up to 64 Mbytes (formatted), streaming tapes for backup, auto-dial modems (2400 baud synchronous) for communications, and flexible disk drives for smaller installations.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Billings_6000_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;GERMAN ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;German advert for the Philips Odyssey 200 model.&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.dieterkoenig.at/ccc/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Dieter Koening&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for this picture&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/magnavox_odyssey200_german-ad_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;DMS-15&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;January 1983 advert.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; The DMS-15 is a DMS-3/F with a built-in 15 MB hard disk.&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/DigitalMicrosys_DMS15_Advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (JUNE 1985)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/olivetti_advert_docile-compatibles_2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;JAPANESE AD&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Picture courtesy of Soichiro Oga / &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://web.kyoto-inet.or.jp/people/s-oga/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Old PC leaflets museum&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/nec_tk80_ad_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;U.K. AD. (DEC. 1985)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Commodore_128_Advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;IN SCHOOLS #3&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/bull_micral-80-22_in-use_3.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;US ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/tandy_1000series_ad_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;U.S. ADVERT #5 (1980)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Advert said:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt;If you could talk to Thomas Edison, he'd tell you what it was like to turn the light on in 1879. You could tell him about some bright idea of the 20th century... particularly, a technological phenomenon that can handle everything from solar heat control to lighting you home via voice command. The Apple personal computer...&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ... With Apple, Edison could've written a program to determine why some filaments burned longer than others...&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Apple_II_Advertd_2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;US ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/INTV_System3_ad_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FIRST U.S. AD (1982)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;A discreet advert and a nice monitor.&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Basis_108_USAdvert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;US ADVERT, JUL 1985&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Byte Magazine&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Ampere_WS1_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;8086 VERSION&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;In september 1982, Seattle Computer provided the 8086 version of the Gazelle with a free set of software: Microsoft MS-DOS, GW-Basic and the Perfect Writer word processor. &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/SeattleComp_Gazelle_Advert_2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;AMTEXT BROCHURE #2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;The brochure says:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt; When you buy, lease or rent word processing equipment from AM Jacquard Systems, you get our total commitment, now and in the future, that assures the successful installation and operation of your AMtext word processing system. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; To support that commitment, we have offices in over 100 cities throughout North America staffed with skilled professionals ready to meet your neads with planning, training. supplies, and service... &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ...The AMtext 100 is a true shared resource, multifunction information system capable of supporting multiple work stations and peripherals simultaneously. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; The Amtext 425 and 425A are powerful stand-alone work stations with a full-page video display &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; The AMtext 225 is a low-cost system that turns electric typewriters into flexible text editors. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; The AMtext product line includes a complete selection of peripheral devices, including telecommunications, an optical character reader. magnetic card reader, phototypesetters, daisy wheel printers. high-speed line and matrix printers, as well as mass storage on floppy and hard disk drive units.  &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Jacquard_J100_AmText_2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;1983 BADGES&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Commodore__64_Badges_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;NEO-GEO ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://spoonman.roarvgm.com/neogeo/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;SpoonMan's Neo-Geo page&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for this picture&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/snk_neogeo_advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;1978 BROCHURE #18&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;As the picture is quite unreadable, we have replaced it with a plain text copy.  &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; In order to provide as much information as possible, we have selected the most frequently asked questions about MSI products for inclu&amp;shy;sion in our catalog. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Questions About the MSI 6800 Computer&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What are the main differences between the MSI 6800 Computer and the MP 6800 Com&amp;shy;puter manufactured by Southwest Technical Products Corporation?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The MSI 6800 Computer is bus compati&amp;shy;ble with the SWTP 6800 system. Both use the SS-50. bus architecture. However, the MSI 6800 overcomes the engineering disadvan&amp;shy;tages associated with the MIKBUG monitor, incomplete address decoding, interface ad&amp;shy;dresses in the middle of user memory, inade&amp;shy;quate power supply, and mother board capacity. The MSI 6800 system has a 20 amp power supply and a heavy duty mother board with 16 slots and gold-plated connectors. Our CPU Board has separate baud rate and system clocks, 4K of EPROM memory and a much improved MIKBUG compatible monitor. MSI interface cards bring all strappable options to a DB-25 connector on the rear panel via a rib&amp;shy;bon cable connector. This permits any terminal to be plugged into the computer without alteration of the interface card. Other advantages of the MSI 6800 are described in this catalog. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Can I use my SWTP memory boards and interface boards in the new MSI 6800 Com&amp;shy;puter?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, since the bus architecture is identical, they will worlk fine. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Can I use the MSI 6800 mother board and power supply only to beef up my SWTP 6800 system?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, the MSI mother board (MB-1) has the same hole centers as the SWTP mother board and will mount easily in the SWTP chassis. However, the MSI interface adapter board (IA-1) must also be used to furnish an interface bus. The MSI power supply (PS-1) may also be used to replace the SWTP supply. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Is the MSI6800 available wired and tested?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, see catalog listings. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Can I use the MSI CPU card in my SWTP 6800 system in order to gain a faster system clock and on board EPROM memory?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, however the MSI power supply should also be used in order to adequately supply the EPROM memory. A MIKBUG replacement monitor must also be used if interface ad&amp;shy;dresses used by MIKBUG are to be retained. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Questions About the FD-8 Disk Memory System&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; I have an SWTP 6800 System. What is needed to hook up your FD..a Floppy Disk Memory to my system?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The FD..a Disk Memory System interfaces to any microprocessor system via a single PIA chip. For the SWTP 6800 System, we furnish our PIA-1 interface card which plugs in directly to port 7 of the interface bus. A ribbon cable then plugs into the interface card and to the disk. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What software is provided with the FD-8 Disk System?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; MSI provides a complete disk operating system software package for use with 6800 based microprocessor systems. The operating system gives the user the capability of having named files at three levels: object code files, source code files for the assembler, and BASIC files. The system contains a coresident as&amp;shy;sembler/editor which can pull source files from disk, assemble, and pass object code to either tape cassette or disk memory. Password pro&amp;shy;tection is available for both program as well as random and sequential data.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; The new TSC editor is now available in a MSI FD-8 disk version. This excellent editor allows very long source files to be stored on disk, edited, and assembled with the object code being placed on disk as well.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; In BASIC, both program as well as random and sequential disk data files are available. All files are named with optional password pro&amp;shy;tection. Other basic programs on disk can be chained to or called as subroutines from a parent program. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What charges are made for software, and what documentation do I receive?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The complete disk operating system, in&amp;shy;cluding the coresident assembler/editor are provided free of charge with the purchase of an FD..a Disk System. A $65.00 charge is made for MSI BASIC. An operating manual for disk oper&amp;shy;ating system, assembler/editor, and BASIC is provided. Partial source documentation is also provided for the input and output routines and other appropriate addresses. In addition, com&amp;shy;plete source documentation is provided for the disk driver subroutines and MINIDOS which allows the user to read or write any desired sector or number of sectors from any beginning disk location to any destination in computer memory. This enables the user to have access to the disk in his own assembly language pro&amp;shy;grams or by direct communication with the control terminal completely independently from the MSI disk operating system. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Is it possible to interface the FD-8 Floppy Disk to microcomputer systems using the 8080, Z80, or 6502 processors? If so, do you provide the technical details on interfacing?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The FD-8 can be connected to any micro&amp;shy;processor via a single PIA chip interface. Elec&amp;shy;tronically, there is no difficulty in interfacing to any system since transfers between the disk and the host computer are carried out via a sector buffer RAM on the disk controller card. Information transfer is under the control of a crystal clock on the controller board, thus mak&amp;shy;ing the FD-8 completely independent from processor speed or clock frequency. It is possi&amp;shy;ble to interface the FD-8 using parallel data ports without a PIA chip, however, the software for interfacing has already been written for both 8080 and 6800 systems using a PIA interface. Since some of the ports are used bi-direction&amp;shy;ally, the PIA interface provides an overall sim&amp;shy;plifi9ation of the interfacing problem. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What software is available for 8080 sys&amp;shy;tems?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; MSI provides complete source listings and documentation for MINIDOS and the disk driver subroutines which have been written for the 8080. This allows the user to have complete access to the disk to write any desired sector or number of sectors from any desired starting location to any desired destination memory address. A complete 8080 based disk operating system is not yet available. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Is your FD-8 Floppy Disk double density?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The MSI Floppy Disk uses the GSI Model 110 drive which has the capability of operating in the double density mode. However, double density operation requires data to be written using a modified FM technique. This requires special data separator and data writing circuitry which is not contained within the present ver&amp;shy;sion of the FD-8. Double density version of the FD-8 will be introduced at a later time.&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/MSI_6800_Brochure_s18.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;GERMAN BROCHURE #1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Volken&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Atari_Stacy_GermanDoc_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;JAPANESE ADVERTISEMENT #2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;She seems quite happy with her new MB-H1 !&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Do you think japanese girls used to bring their H1 to school ?!&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Hitachi_mbh1_pub2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (1980)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Dated december 1980&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/tandy_trs80-model1_ad_grande-ouverture_s.gif</link>
        </advert>
    </adverts>
    <batteries></batteries>
    <builtInGames>Unknown</builtInGames>
    <buttons></buttons>
    <colors>green and black</colors>
    <controllers></controllers>
    <coprocessor>Unknown</coprocessor>
    <cpu>Unknown</cpu>
    <description>
The Imlac PDS-1 is a graphical minicomputer made by Imlac Corporation (founded in 1968) of Needham, Massachusetts. The PDS-1 debuted in 1970 and is considered to be the predecessor of all later graphical minicomputers and modern computer workstations. The PDS-1 had a built-in display list processor and 4096 16-bit words of core RAM. The PDS-1 used a vector display processor for displaying vector graphics as opposed to the raster graphics of modern computer displays. The PDS-1 was often used with another flagship Imlac product, a typesetting program called CES.

The PDS-1 was used in many pioneering computer applications. The FRESS hypertext system had enhanced capability and usability if accessed from a PDS-1 system; the user could make hyperlinks with a light pen and create them simply with a couple of keystrokes. Multi-window editing on FRESS was also possible when using the PDS-1.

The PDS-1 also had the capability to run remote graphical programs such as those that ran on the Stanford AI Lab's main computer. The PDS-1 was also able to run Mazewar, the first online multiplayer computer game. The PDS-1 connected to a host PDP-10 computer (located at MIT) running ITS over Arpanet and the Mazewar program. Up to 8 players running PDS-1 minicomputers or other terminals could access MIT's Mazewar host. The PDS-1 was also important during the early days of Arpanet when network graphics protocols were under consideration.

Source: Wikipedia
 


</description>
    <emulators/>
    <graphics>vector display</graphics>
    <gun></gun>
    <hardwares/>
    <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Imlac_PDS-1D_2s.jpg</image>
    <keyboard>Full-stroke keyboard</keyboard>
    <language>Unknown</language>
    <links>
        <link>http://history-computer.com/ModernComputer/Personal/Imlac.html</link>
        <link>http://www.blinkenlights.com/classiccmp/imlac/</link>
        <link>http://www.ubanproductions.com/imlac.html</link>
    </links>
    <manufacturer>Imlac</manufacturer>
    <media></media>
    <name>PDS-1</name>
    <numGames></numGames>
    <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
    <peripherals>Unknown</peripherals>
    <ports>Unknown</ports>
    <power>Unknown</power>
    <price>Unknown</price>
    <production>Unknown</production>
    <ram>4096 16-bit words</ram>
    <rom>Unknown</rom>
    <screenshots>
        <shot>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;IMLAC PDS-1D&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.ubanproductions.com/imlac.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;www.ubanproductions.com&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for this picture&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/Imlac_PDS-1D_2.jpg</link>
        </shot>
    </screenshots>
    <size>Unknown</size>
    <sound>Unknown</sound>
    <speed>Unknown</speed>
    <switches></switches>
    <text></text>
    <type>Professional Computer</type>
    <vram>Unknown</vram>
    <year>1970</year>
</computer>
