<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computer>
    <adverts>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH AD (JAN. 1980)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/acs-1007_ad_1980.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (DECEMBER 1981)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;At 12 years old, Nicolas discovered he was the terror of the aliens&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/atari_2600_ad_nicolas.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;JAPANESE ADVERT #3&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://osaki.cool.ne.jp/hc/computer/canon/canon.html#x07&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Handheld computer &amp;amp; Pocket calculator Museum&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for this picture&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/canon_x07_jap-advert_2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;U.S. ADVERT (1979)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Advert said:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt;You know about computers. In fact, you probably own one now. One that you might be thinking of expanding. We have a better idea. Take a giant step into the personal computing future with an amazing, new C4P from Ohio Scientific...&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ...The C4P is an outstanding premium computer - years ahead of the market. We know because there's nothing quite like it for the price, anywhere. And probably won't be for a very long time.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; About the DISPLAY paragraph:&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;256 x 512 effective graphic points&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Kurt Vogel&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; rectifies:&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; The C4P did NOT have a 256x512 graphics mode!  If it had, that would have been amazing for the price way back then.  Instead, it had a 32x64 character display and claimed that because each character was made up of a 8x8 grid that that was supposed to count as 256x512 graphics.  Even given that they used an extended 8 bit character set that included special line and shape characters, you were NEVER able to address indivual pixels!&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;       &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Ohio_C4P_Advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;GERMAN ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;A computer, which grows with your requirements&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Joscelyn Flores&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Casio_FP6000_GermAdvert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;1978 BROCHURE #19&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;As the picture is quite unreadable, we have replaced it with a plain text copy.  &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What kind of diskettes do you recommend for use with the FD-8?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; We have our diskettes manufactured by the Dysan Corporation. They are packaged for us under the MSI label and have proven to be the most reliable diskettes available for use with the FD-8. We have tried other manufactur&amp;shy;ers but have found none to be as reliable as Dysan. We pay more money for Dysan diskettes and, as a result, cannot offer them at a price quite as competitive as some other manufac&amp;shy;turers. However, we feel that the reliability is most important. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Does the FD-8 use IBM compatible format?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The FD-8 is not IBM compatible since we use hard-sectoring on the diskette. Our format uses 16 sectors of 256 data bytes each per track. In addition, track and sector identification, checksum (CRC), and other error checking information is written on each sector in addition to the data. This gives a total capacity of 315,392 bytes of data which can be stored per diskette. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What are diskette hardholes, and what do they do?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Hardholes are small mylar doughnuts which may be affixed to the center hole of a diskette for additional protection. It is possible to damage the center hole of a diskette if it is not properly centered at the time the disk drive door is closed. The mylar doughnut serves to reinforce the center hole of the diskette and give it additional protection against damage. The hard hole also provides for additional fric&amp;shy;tion between the diskette and the clamping hub in order to provent slippage of the diskette dur&amp;shy;ing rotation. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Does MSI offer application software packages?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; MSI is in the process of developing ap&amp;shy;plication software for use with the FD-8 System. We will be offering a library of standard busi&amp;shy;ness programs for accounting, inventory and mail list applications in the near future. These programs will be written in BASIC using the disk data file capability of the FD-8. The availability of application software will be announced in periodic MSI newsletters and will be made available to FD-8 users for a small copying charge plus the cost of the diskette. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Does a user program library exist for the MSI FD-8 Disk System?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; We are in the process of organizing a user group for the FD-8. Users of the FD-8 System are encouraged to submit programs which may be included in the user library. Member&amp;shy;ship in the user group may be achieved by either submitting a program for publication or by payment of a nominal membership fee. Membership then entitles the user to receive periodic listings of user library contents and newsletters. Programs contained within the user library will be made available for a small copying charge. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What is the difference between MSI TAPE BASIC and MSI BASIC used with the FD-8 Disk System?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; We have added several features to the MSI version of BASIC. We offer multiple statements per line, user defined verbs, a string&amp;shy;length command which allows strings up to 128 characters to be used, and have increased the speed of execution. In addition, we have completely removed the dependence upon the MIKBUG ROM and MIKBUG RAM areas. The stack pointers have been moved to the user program area, and the input/output routines for each of the ports are fully documented so that these can be easily changed. Interrupts are now allowed and can be used to vector the program to a user subroutine and then return to BASIC. We are also developing multi-user BASIC which will be released in the near future. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Can MSI BASIC and the disk operating system be relocated?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Essentially, no difference exists between the two versions of BASIC insofar as the BASIC interpreter is concerned. The tape version has disk and DOS commands removed from its library. The interpreter resides from memory location $0100 to $1 FFF in both versions. In addition, memory locations below $0100 are used as pointers. In the Disk version, memory locations from $2000 - $2FFF are used to con&amp;shy;tain disk driver subroutines, DOS, and other file handling routines. User memory begins at $2000 for the tape version and $3800 in the Disk version of BASIC. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What is the difference between SWTP 8K BASIC and MSI BASIC?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; It is not considered feasible to attempt relocation of these programs since so many of the individual routines which are used in the disk operating system are integrated. It would require a major revision of the disk operating system, BASIC, coresident assembler/editor and other associated utility programs before such a relocation could be performed. However, a version of MSI BASIC will soon be available on PROM which will reside at a high memory location. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; How difficult is it to run MSI BASIC and the disk operating system on the Motorola Ex&amp;shy;orciser, or other 6800 based microcomputer systems?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The primary changes which must be made are in the input and output character routines. These routines must be changed in all MSI software so as to be compatible with the sys&amp;shy;tem on which software is running. In addition, the PIA Interface which communicates with the disk, the FD-8, is presently located at mem&amp;shy;ory address $801 C. A PIA residing at this ad&amp;shy;dress will also be necessary, or alternatively, this address must also be changed in the disk driver subroutines. Several different versions of the MSI software package are currently being developed for use with other 6800 systems. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Will MSI BASIC handle tape commands as well as disk?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, the commands TSAVE AND TLOAD are used with the tape, whereas the commands SAVE and LOAD are reserved for use with the disk. It is also possible to place a label at the front of a block which is saved on tape. When this label is specified during a LOAD opera&amp;shy;tion, the program will search for the appropriate block on tape before loading in the information which has been stored on the tape. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Will MSI BASIC handle data files?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, both random and sequential data files are available for the disk system under MSI BASIC. Named files for object code, source code, BASIC program, and BASIC data files are all available. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; I have heard that 1702A PROMs are too slow for use with 6800 systems running at full clock speed. Is this true?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; This is not true, if the memory addressing scheme employed by MSI is used to address the 1702A PROMs. The MSI PROM/RAM Board does not employ Phase 2 of the clock in the memory addressing scheme. This permits a tolerable memory access time of approxi&amp;shy;mately 9OQns. MSI uses 650ns access time 1702A PROMs in all applications. This provides completely satisfactory reliability of operation. We have experienced no problems whatsoever when using fast 1702As. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Can I buy a Bootstrap routine on PROM in order to bring the disk system into operation quickly?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, MSI is presently delivering a 512 byte Bootstrap Program known as Short Boot. This routine is available on a two-PROM set using 1702A PROMs for use with the MSI PROM/RAM Board. Short Boot and the PROM Board are delivered with most Disk Systems. This allows the disk to be placed into operation by simply executing the Bootstrap routine which is orged at $COOO. The system then responds immediately with DOS READY and programs may then be called immediately by file name. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; I am interested in purchasing MSI software but am having a hard time evaluating its use&amp;shy;fulness. May I purchase the documentation for your disk system and BASIC separately for evaluation?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, the complete operating manual for the FD-8 Disk System may be purchased sep&amp;shy;arately for $35.00. This manual includes as&amp;shy;se&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/MSI_6800_Brochure_s19.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;UK ADVERT, OCT. 1983&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Advert says:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt; A computer that, for the first time, works with you rather than just for you. Hardware and Software co-ordinating perfectly, Apricot arrives complete and ready to work.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; The MicroScreen on the keyboard, unique to Apricot, performs a variety of practical functions as a calculator, calendar, time display, and as a window on the screen. Most signifIcantly the MicroScreen prompts and assists the user by presenting simple options whilst running applications.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Incorporating the very latest advances in computer technology, Apricot uses 31/2&amp;quot; pocket-size diskettes. Secure and compact, yet offering increased storage capacity.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; As you'd expect with a 4th generation system, Apricot offers true 16-bit processing, multi-processor architecture and 256k RAM as standard. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; With Pulsar 16-bit business software and compatibility with the best selling ACT Sirius 1 and IBM PC, Apricot already has the largest available software library. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Apricot includes over &amp;pound;750 of software&amp;shy; - SuperCalc spreadsheet, business and communications software - to ensure that your system is immediately effective. And because executives are not office bound, Apricot offers portability, a further feature aimed at improving efficiency.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Powerful sleek and sophisticated and all at an amazing 4th generation price.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Act_Apricot_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;COMPACT VERSION&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Promotional picture; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Diego Barizo&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; adds:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; In the picture of the compact version of the TK3000, the joystick, a TRS-80 de luxe joystick, and the screen is quite similar to that of a flight simulator for the TRS-CoCo. Maybe they had one behind the monitor? &amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Roberto Isiri&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Microdigital_TK3000_CompactAd_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH AD (JULY 1984)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/sinclair_zx81_advert-ordi-5-vitesses.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (1984)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Kaypro, it runs&amp;quot; ! &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Kaypro, the computer which can be carried away&amp;quot; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Elected Transportable Computer of the year&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/kaypro_ad_camarche_s.gif</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT. PAGE #1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/symag_micromachine_4000_pub.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/sinclair_spectrum-plus_advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;PROMOTIONAL LEAFLET&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/fairchild_channelf_leaflet_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;U.S. AD. JUNE 1983&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Kaypro_II_KaycompAd_5.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FIRST AD.&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;January 1983&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Telcon needed customers payments before manufacturing the systems:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Upon receipt of your check, we will forward an end-user agreement. Allow 6 to 8 weeks for delivery of the units. &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Telcon_Zorba_Advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;USA RADIO SHACK CATALOG (1991)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/tandy_wp2_ad_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;RUSSIAN ADVERT - PAGE 1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to Taras Ponomarev for this advert&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/agat_ad-elorg_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (JAN. 1983)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/philips_c52_advert_1s.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;ADVERT #1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;The display says: &amp;quot;Personal computer Pravetz 82&amp;quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Bojidar Stefanov&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Pravetz_Imko_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;GERMAN ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;German advert for the Philips Odyssey 200 model.&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.dieterkoenig.at/ccc/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Dieter Koening&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for this picture&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/magnavox_odyssey200_german-ad_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;CHARLIE CHAPLIN #6&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;From Personal Computing, July 1982 issue.&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Courtesy of &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.aci.com.pl/mwichary/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Attached&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/IBM_5150_ChaplinAdvert_6.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (JUNE 1985)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Thomson, the micro capital&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/thomson_mo5_ad_capitale-micro.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;US ADVERT (1982)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;This advert introduced three new Digital professional computers: the &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Professional 300 Series&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;, the &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;DECmate II&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;, and the &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Rainbow 100&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Advert said: &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt;All that personal computers needed were a few professional standards. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Until now, manufacturer have made personal computers that were a hopeful compromise between home and use business. But now, Digital Equipment Corporation offers the first personal computers designed and built strictly for professional use. And since different professionals have different needs, Digital is introducing not one, but three personal computers made to professional standards.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/digital_DecMate2_Advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;ADVERT #4 (1982)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Circa September, 1982.  This is likely one of the final Commodore advertisements for the VIC-20, as the C64 was soon to be launched.&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Commodore_Vic20_Advert_4.jpg</link>
        </advert>
    </adverts>
    <batteries></batteries>
    <builtInGames>F-Basic available on disk</builtInGames>
    <buttons></buttons>
    <colors>16</colors>
    <controllers></controllers>
    <coprocessor></coprocessor>
    <cpu>MBL 6809E</cpu>
    <description>
The FM-11 AD2 is an evolution of the FM-11 AD. It is delivered with the OS-9 operating system.

There was also a FM-11 AD2+ model with enhanced features like 256 KB RAM instead of 128 KB.

Torsten Dittel, from Germany, adds:
Looks like the FM11 AD2 had an HD63C09EP from Hitachi installed. It was a
PIN/Code compatible CMOS/3MHz version of the MC68B09E from Motorola. For licensing reasons Hitachi kept as a &amp;quot;secret&amp;quot; that it has a special
native mode with additional instructions/registers/capabilities and more
speed. I don't think these features were used in the stock OS-9 Level II
installed.
With our CoCo3s and the CPU changed to an HD63C09EP we use a
special OS-9 version called NitrOS9 to take advantage of this native
mode.

Gern, from Japan, reports:
I've owned FM-11AD2, used for 3 years. Here I wanna introduce unique aspect of this wonderful machine.
One of the interesting feature of FM-11 series is CPU cards. All FM-11 without BS model equipped a couple of CPU slots and one is filled with 6809. Z80 and 8088 CPU card was available from FUJITSU. 68000 card was available from third party. CP/M-80/86 was available for each CPU cards. (But everytime system boots from 6809 ;-)
FM-11BS might be only model come with 8088.
After ST/AD/EX line-up, AD2 and BS replaced, then AD2+ followed. OS-9 was packaged with AD2/AD2+. AD2+ is supposed to be the longest one which FUJITSU manufactured because amazing multitask was appropriate for many  industrial devices. When I was noticed from final lots of FM-11AD2+ from FUJITSU, over 2 following generation FM series were extinct.


 


</description>
    <emulators/>
    <graphics>640 x 400, 640 x 200</graphics>
    <gun></gun>
    <hardwares/>
    <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/fujitsu_fm11ad2_1.jpg</image>
    <keyboard>Complete professional keyboard with function keys and separated numeric keypad (JIS standard). 98 keys.</keyboard>
    <language>F-Basic available on disk</language>
    <links>
        <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=1217</link>
        <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=381</link>
        <link>computer.asp?st=1&amp;amp;c=379</link>
    </links>
    <manufacturer>Fujitsu</manufacturer>
    <media>1 or 2 x 5.25'' disk drives (2DD, 320 KB), optional 10 MB hard disk</media>
    <name>FM 11 AD 2</name>
    <numGames></numGames>
    <origin>Japan</origin>
    <peripherals></peripherals>
    <ports>Tape-recorder interface (1600 baud), parallel/Centronics connector, RS-232c, RGB video output, Composite video output, TV (RF) video output, light-pen interface, 7 expansion slots</ports>
    <power>Built-in PSU</power>
    <price></price>
    <production></production>
    <ram>128 KB (up to 1 MB)</ram>
    <rom>24 KB</rom>
    <screenshots>
        <shot>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FM 11 AD2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/fujitsu_fm11ad2.jpg</link>
        </shot>
    </screenshots>
    <size>464 (W) x 360 (D) x 153 (H) mm / 13 kg</size>
    <sound>Unknown</sound>
    <speed>2 Mhz</speed>
    <switches></switches>
    <text>40 x 20, 40 x 25, 80 x 20, 80 x 25</text>
    <type>Home Computer</type>
    <vram>192 KB</vram>
    <year>1984</year>
</computer>
