<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<computer>
    <adverts>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;SWEDISH ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/stupid_sweden-commodore.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH AD&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Advert said : &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ''The computer which carried away America&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; ''With its portable computers, Compaq became world number two on the market of the 16 bits computers. With a turnover of 240 million dollars in one year and a half, this young company established in Houston obtained the growth rate record of the American economic history.&amp;quot; &amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Compaq_PortablePlus_Advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (JUNE 1985)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Thomson, the micro capital&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/thomson_mo5_ad_capitale-micro.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (1984)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/mb_vectrex_ad_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT.&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/toshiba_hx10_pub.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;LAST SALES&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;This advert (a bargain!) was published in the U.K. in September 1987&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Memotech_MTX512_Advert_3.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;ADVERT #1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;The display says: &amp;quot;Personal computer Pravetz 82&amp;quot;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Bojidar Stefanov&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Pravetz_Imko_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH AD #3 (1984)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;The guy on the right is &amp;quot;Sidney&amp;quot;, a well known french break dancer back in 1984 !&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/acorn_electron_ad2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (APRIL1982)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;The Sinclair Phenomenon&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/sinclair_zx81_pub_phenomene_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;1978 BROCHURE #19&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;As the picture is quite unreadable, we have replaced it with a plain text copy.  &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What kind of diskettes do you recommend for use with the FD-8?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; We have our diskettes manufactured by the Dysan Corporation. They are packaged for us under the MSI label and have proven to be the most reliable diskettes available for use with the FD-8. We have tried other manufactur&amp;shy;ers but have found none to be as reliable as Dysan. We pay more money for Dysan diskettes and, as a result, cannot offer them at a price quite as competitive as some other manufac&amp;shy;turers. However, we feel that the reliability is most important. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Does the FD-8 use IBM compatible format?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The FD-8 is not IBM compatible since we use hard-sectoring on the diskette. Our format uses 16 sectors of 256 data bytes each per track. In addition, track and sector identification, checksum (CRC), and other error checking information is written on each sector in addition to the data. This gives a total capacity of 315,392 bytes of data which can be stored per diskette. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What are diskette hardholes, and what do they do?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Hardholes are small mylar doughnuts which may be affixed to the center hole of a diskette for additional protection. It is possible to damage the center hole of a diskette if it is not properly centered at the time the disk drive door is closed. The mylar doughnut serves to reinforce the center hole of the diskette and give it additional protection against damage. The hard hole also provides for additional fric&amp;shy;tion between the diskette and the clamping hub in order to provent slippage of the diskette dur&amp;shy;ing rotation. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Does MSI offer application software packages?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; MSI is in the process of developing ap&amp;shy;plication software for use with the FD-8 System. We will be offering a library of standard busi&amp;shy;ness programs for accounting, inventory and mail list applications in the near future. These programs will be written in BASIC using the disk data file capability of the FD-8. The availability of application software will be announced in periodic MSI newsletters and will be made available to FD-8 users for a small copying charge plus the cost of the diskette. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Does a user program library exist for the MSI FD-8 Disk System?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; We are in the process of organizing a user group for the FD-8. Users of the FD-8 System are encouraged to submit programs which may be included in the user library. Member&amp;shy;ship in the user group may be achieved by either submitting a program for publication or by payment of a nominal membership fee. Membership then entitles the user to receive periodic listings of user library contents and newsletters. Programs contained within the user library will be made available for a small copying charge. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What is the difference between MSI TAPE BASIC and MSI BASIC used with the FD-8 Disk System?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; We have added several features to the MSI version of BASIC. We offer multiple statements per line, user defined verbs, a string&amp;shy;length command which allows strings up to 128 characters to be used, and have increased the speed of execution. In addition, we have completely removed the dependence upon the MIKBUG ROM and MIKBUG RAM areas. The stack pointers have been moved to the user program area, and the input/output routines for each of the ports are fully documented so that these can be easily changed. Interrupts are now allowed and can be used to vector the program to a user subroutine and then return to BASIC. We are also developing multi-user BASIC which will be released in the near future. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Can MSI BASIC and the disk operating system be relocated?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Essentially, no difference exists between the two versions of BASIC insofar as the BASIC interpreter is concerned. The tape version has disk and DOS commands removed from its library. The interpreter resides from memory location $0100 to $1 FFF in both versions. In addition, memory locations below $0100 are used as pointers. In the Disk version, memory locations from $2000 - $2FFF are used to con&amp;shy;tain disk driver subroutines, DOS, and other file handling routines. User memory begins at $2000 for the tape version and $3800 in the Disk version of BASIC. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; What is the difference between SWTP 8K BASIC and MSI BASIC?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; It is not considered feasible to attempt relocation of these programs since so many of the individual routines which are used in the disk operating system are integrated. It would require a major revision of the disk operating system, BASIC, coresident assembler/editor and other associated utility programs before such a relocation could be performed. However, a version of MSI BASIC will soon be available on PROM which will reside at a high memory location. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; How difficult is it to run MSI BASIC and the disk operating system on the Motorola Ex&amp;shy;orciser, or other 6800 based microcomputer systems?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; The primary changes which must be made are in the input and output character routines. These routines must be changed in all MSI software so as to be compatible with the sys&amp;shy;tem on which software is running. In addition, the PIA Interface which communicates with the disk, the FD-8, is presently located at mem&amp;shy;ory address $801 C. A PIA residing at this ad&amp;shy;dress will also be necessary, or alternatively, this address must also be changed in the disk driver subroutines. Several different versions of the MSI software package are currently being developed for use with other 6800 systems. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Will MSI BASIC handle tape commands as well as disk?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, the commands TSAVE AND TLOAD are used with the tape, whereas the commands SAVE and LOAD are reserved for use with the disk. It is also possible to place a label at the front of a block which is saved on tape. When this label is specified during a LOAD opera&amp;shy;tion, the program will search for the appropriate block on tape before loading in the information which has been stored on the tape. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Will MSI BASIC handle data files?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, both random and sequential data files are available for the disk system under MSI BASIC. Named files for object code, source code, BASIC program, and BASIC data files are all available. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; I have heard that 1702A PROMs are too slow for use with 6800 systems running at full clock speed. Is this true?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; This is not true, if the memory addressing scheme employed by MSI is used to address the 1702A PROMs. The MSI PROM/RAM Board does not employ Phase 2 of the clock in the memory addressing scheme. This permits a tolerable memory access time of approxi&amp;shy;mately 9OQns. MSI uses 650ns access time 1702A PROMs in all applications. This provides completely satisfactory reliability of operation. We have experienced no problems whatsoever when using fast 1702As. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Can I buy a Bootstrap routine on PROM in order to bring the disk system into operation quickly?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, MSI is presently delivering a 512 byte Bootstrap Program known as Short Boot. This routine is available on a two-PROM set using 1702A PROMs for use with the MSI PROM/RAM Board. Short Boot and the PROM Board are delivered with most Disk Systems. This allows the disk to be placed into operation by simply executing the Bootstrap routine which is orged at $COOO. The system then responds immediately with DOS READY and programs may then be called immediately by file name. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Q.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; I am interested in purchasing MSI software but am having a hard time evaluating its use&amp;shy;fulness. May I purchase the documentation for your disk system and BASIC separately for evaluation?&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;A.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Yes, the complete operating manual for the FD-8 Disk System may be purchased sep&amp;shy;arately for $35.00. This manual includes as&amp;shy;se&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/MSI_6800_Brochure_s19.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;M-SERIES BROCHURE - PAGE 3&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to Juraj Mucko for this picture&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/panasonic_jd_flyer_3.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH ADVERT (DEC. 1982)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Christmas accounts&amp;quot; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Casio, it counts&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/casio_fx702p_advert_2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;JAPANESE ADVERT.&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;She seems so happy to have an Hit-Bit...&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/sony_HB-75_advert.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;US ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Thanks to Tim_K for this picture&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/vectrex_ad-high-perfomance-machine.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH AD (JUNE 1986)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;In 1986, the Alphatronic PC was bargained in many broker shops for a low price.&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/triumph-adler_alphatronic_pc_pub_alpax.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;ADVERT #1&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Picture courtesy of &amp;lt;a href=&amp;sect;http://www.sbrowning.com/vintage&amp;sect;&amp;gt;Steve Browning, www.sbrowning.com/vintage&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/sinclair_zx80_advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;US ADVERT, AUG. 1983&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Courtesy of &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.aci.com.pl/mwichary/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Attached&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Osborne_Executive_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;ADVERT&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Picture courtesy of &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.sbrowning.com/vintage&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Steve Browning, www.sbrowning.com/vintage&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/apple_advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;UK ADVERT, OCT. 1983&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;From Personal Computer World magazine.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Advert says:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;#666666&amp;quot;&amp;gt; This is an entirely new computer system. It was designed with both eyes fixed firmly on the future. So that whatever shape the future takes, we'll be able to fit it into the system. Just as simply as the peripherals and software already available fit into the system. That way, the system will grow with you. And you'll never get left behind. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Based around the Z80A microprocessor, and utilising Microsoft BASIC, Aquarius has 8K ROM and 4K RAM resident within its console. It is able to provide up to 16 colours and resolution of 320 x 192, and generates its sound directly through the television's speakers. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; With twin cartridge ports, the mini-expander allows simultaneous use of additional RAM and software cartrldges. Twin disc game hand controls are included and the unit provides two additional sound channels. The 16K RAM cartridge plugs into either the console or the mini-expander, increasing Aquarius's RAM capacity to 20K. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; With the ability to reproduce the entire graphic and character set of Aquarius at 80 characters a second, the printer's 40 column output allows transcription of the complete monitor image. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Using standard audio cassettes, the data recorder provides storage for programs and information, and allows the use of cassette based software. Incorporating a digital tape counter and transmission indicator, it operates sequential searching. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; A large number of games, designed to take advantage of Aquarius's sophisticated colour and sound capabilities, are available on cartridges that plug into the console either direct, or through the mini-expander. Cassette based games can be used via the data recorder. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; A wide range of preprogrammed cartridges is available, including the LOGO teaching program and practical home data systems like FILEFORM and the spreadsheet calculator package FINFORM. &amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/Mattel_Aquarius_Advert_s1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;PROMOTIONAL LEAFLET #2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/fairchild_channelf_leaflet_2.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;US ADVERT (MAY 1983)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;No info in this advert about the display that could be used (TV, composite, colour, B/W?)&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/smt_piedpiper_advert_1982[2]_s.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;FRENCH AD (JAN. 1980)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/tandy_trs80-model1_ad_computercenter_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;ADVERT #2&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;petitgris&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Picture courtesy of &amp;lt;a href=&amp;sect;http://www.sbrowning.com/vintage&amp;sect;&amp;gt;Steve Browning, www.sbrowning.com/vintage&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/timex_1000_advert_1.jpg</link>
        </advert>
        <advert>
            <description>&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;font color=&amp;quot;red&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;PROMO PIC #6&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;Thanks to its optional modem, the TO-7/70 could be connected to the Teletel communication network. This skilled photograph is browsing the Liberation (popular french newspaper) site. &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; But there are still no cables shown here ! How the whole system is running ?!&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;</description>
            <link>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/adverts/thomson_to770_pub-libe.jpg</link>
        </advert>
    </adverts>
    <batteries></batteries>
    <builtInGames>Mini-cassette</builtInGames>
    <buttons></buttons>
    <colors>None</colors>
    <controllers></controllers>
    <coprocessor></coprocessor>
    <cpu>Motorola 6800</cpu>
    <description>
The &amp;quot;Miniterm&amp;quot; portable computer terminal was the Computer Devices Incorporated's primary product.

This &amp;quot;hand-carried&amp;quot; computer was preprogrammed to lead sales, manufacturing, and other untrained in computer operation through data processing tasks. Stored on a minicassette, the program was called up automatically when the computer is switched on.

Model 1206/PAT had a 64k processor with 32k RAM and included a modem acoustic coupler, and an 80-column thermal printer that could produce 50 characters per second. Programs were developped in Basic or in Motorola 6800 assembly language on a companion unit.

Options included a 132-column printer, alphanumeric bar-code reader, and a 1.44 MB disk drive.
_______________________</description>
    <emulators/>
    <graphics>Unknown</graphics>
    <gun></gun>
    <hardwares/>
    <image>http://www.old-computers.com/museum/photos/cdi_miniterm.jpg</image>
    <keyboard>Full-stroke keyboard</keyboard>
    <language></language>
    <links/>
    <manufacturer>Computer Devices Incorporated</manufacturer>
    <media>Mini-cassette</media>
    <name>Miniterm</name>
    <numGames></numGames>
    <origin>U.S.A.</origin>
    <peripherals>132 column printer, alphanumeric bar-code reader, 1.44 MB disk drive.</peripherals>
    <ports>Unknown</ports>
    <power>Unknown</power>
    <price>About $5,000</price>
    <production></production>
    <ram>32 KB</ram>
    <rom>About 20 KB</rom>
    <screenshots/>
    <size>17 lbs</size>
    <sound>Unknown,</sound>
    <speed></speed>
    <switches></switches>
    <text>Unknown</text>
    <type>Professional Computer</type>
    <vram></vram>
    <year>1980</year>
</computer>
